<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Minsuk Kang</title>
    <link>https://kangminsuk.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Minsuk Kang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kangminsuk.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Subscribe</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/subscribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/subscribe/</guid>
      <description> RSS Feeds English 한국어 Occasional Emails </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<style>
  footer {display: none;}
</style>

<h3>RSS Feeds</h3>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://kangminsuk.com/blog/index.xml">English</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://kangminsuk.com/ko/blog/index.xml">한국어</a></li>
</ul>

<h3>Occasional Emails</h3>
<form
  action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/kangminsuk"
  method="post"
  target="popupwindow"
  onsubmit="window.open('https://buttondown.email/kangminsuk', 'popupwindow')"
  class="embeddable-buttondown-form"
>
  <input type="email" placeholder="Enter your email" size="15" name="email" id="bd-email" />
  
  <input type="submit" value="Subscribe" />
</form>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letter</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/message/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/message/</guid>
      <description> Letter Keep this field blank </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<style>
  p.byline {display: none;}
  footer {display: none;}
  textarea {width: fit-content;}
  button,
  input,
  select,
  content,
  .field {
    margin-bottom: 15px;
  }
  label {
  width: 150px; 
  text-align: right;
  margin-right: 10px;
  }
  input[type="text"] {
  width: 200px; 
  line-height: 1.5;
  }
</style>

<h2>Letter</h2>

<form action="https://riku.miso.town/submit?user_id=42&label=blog" method="post">
  <input type="hidden" name="redirect" value="https://kangminsuk.com/thank-you">

  <div class="field">
    <textarea name="message" placeholder="What's up?" id="letter" required></textarea>
  </div>

  <div class="submit">
  <input type="submit" value="Send">
  </div>
  
  <div style="display:none;">
    <label for="honeypot">Keep this field blank</label>
    <input type="text" id="honeypot" name="honeypot">
  </div>
</form>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sometimes I just feel you</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/feel-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/feel-you/</guid>
      <description> Sometimes I just feel you When the wind blows through the window When the music blasts from the speaker When the cats rest on the desk I feel you are here Watching over me Thinking I am living your life</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[




<pre tabindex="0"><code>Sometimes I just feel you

When the wind blows through the window
When the music blasts from the speaker
When the cats rest on the desk

I feel you are here
Watching over me
Thinking I am living your life</code></pre>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The City I Want to Live In</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/city-i-want-to-live-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/city-i-want-to-live-in/</guid>
      <description>This is a translated version of Kang&amp;rsquo;s first &amp;amp; second essays of a series &amp;ldquo;Where Do I Want to Live?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Born in Jeonju, I’ve wandered through Haian, Shanghai, Harbin, State College, Boston, Saint Paul, Seoul, and Jeju. One would think I&amp;rsquo;d want to settle down by now, but I often feel a pull to find a place that suits me better.&#xA;When moving from Seoul to Jeju, I thought it didn’t matter where I lived as long as I had the internet.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This is a translated version of <a href="https://jagunbae.com/where-1/">Kang&rsquo;s first &amp; second essays</a> of a series &ldquo;Where Do I Want to Live?&rdquo;</em></p>
<p><img src="https://jagunbae.com/content/images/size/w2000/2024/05/IMG_0672.webp" alt="Munich">
Born in Jeonju, I’ve wandered through Haian, Shanghai, Harbin, State College, Boston, Saint Paul, Seoul, and Jeju. One would think I&rsquo;d want to settle down by now, but I often feel a pull to find a place that suits me better.</p>
<p>When moving from Seoul to Jeju, I thought it didn’t matter where I lived as long as I had the internet. For someone who studies, creates, and spends leisure time online, what difference does it make if I&rsquo;m in Gangnam or Ido-dong? But the longer I live in Jeju, running my tiny content company, the more I wonder. Where should I live? Can I find an environment that fits my lifestyle?</p>
<p>Before tackling the big question of “Where should I live?” I want to list the features of my ideal city (knowing that a perfect environment meeting all these criteria doesn’t exist).</p>
<h2 id="safety">Safety</h2>
<p><img src="https://jagunbae.com/content/images/2024/05/Smoke-bomb-attacks-explosion-detonation-Boston-Marathon-April-15-2013-2.webp" alt="Boston Marathon bombing"></p>
<p>When I was in high school near Boston, I sometimes took a 90-minute bus ride into the city on weekends. One day, I was considering booking an appointment at a Japanese hair salon in Boston.</p>
<p>My housemate said, “Isn’t today the Boston Marathon? Traffic will be terrible.”</p>
<p>“Oh, right.”</p>
<p>As I stayed in and watched my laptop, news broke of a bomb exploding at the marathon. I was shocked. I turned on the TV and saw military helicopters and messages advising everyone to stay indoors. What if the bomber was hiding nearby? I stared at the screen, terrified.</p>
<p>Living in the U.S., I realized the importance of safety many times. Once, a knife-wielding robber swept through a store in New York as I was buying a phone. Another time, I got an alert about a shooting near my college campus.</p>
<p>No place is 100% safe, but I want to live without fear. A neighborhood isn’t livable if you hear gunshots outside.</p>
<h2 id="pedestrian-and-bicycle-friendly">Pedestrian and Bicycle-Friendly</h2>
<p><img src="https://jagunbae.com/content/images/2024/05/amsterdam-tour-bicycle-group-800x450.webp" alt="Amsterdam&rsquo;s bike roads"></p>
<p>Reading Jane Jacobs’ <em>The Death and Life of Great American Cities</em>, I understood U.S. urban design deeply. To summarize its ideas: In a car-centric society, the wealthy move to the suburbs and commute to downtown. ➙ Cities expand endlessly. ➙ Traffic worsens, so sidewalks are removed to widen roads. ➙ With reduced population density, living without a car becomes impossible. ➙ Downtown becomes desolate at night, and those who can’t afford cars suffer greatly.</p>
<p>I dislike cities where there are more cars than people. Walking in Jeju City, surrounded by cars on streets without sidewalks, reminds me of Jacobs&rsquo; teachings. My wife and I used to bike everywhere but gave up and got a car. How can you bike without bike lanes? On sidewalks, we were a nuisance; on roads, we were constantly honked at. Biking meant choosing between these two terrible options.</p>
<p>Nothing frustrates me more than being surrounded by cars. Once, after signaling and ensuring enough space, I changed lanes. A man pulled up beside us, rolled down his window, and yelled, “Hey! Roll down your window, you fucking asshole!” “Just ignore him,” I told my wife as we turned. It left me feeling very down. What made him so angry? Would he have cursed at my face if I had rolled down my window?</p>
<p>I still try to walk or take the bus, but living in a car-dependent area feels stifling. Watching politicians campaign to cars, not people, during the elections made me feel bitter. Living in Jeju might seem like living amid green nature, but the reality is a car-dominated hell. I long to live in a city where walking or biking makes sense.</p>
<h2 id="parks-and-lawns">Parks and Lawns</h2>
<p><img src="https://jagunbae.com/content/images/size/w2000/2024/05/IMG_2803.webp" alt="Jeju&rsquo;s oreums">
Reading that “Cafes serve as parks for Koreans living in cities without resting places,” I nodded in agreement. How nice would it be to have parks and lawns nearby for a relaxing walk? Though there are a few playgrounds near my home, they’re essentially for kids.</p>
<p>I loved walking along Gyeongchun Line Forest Park when I lived in Gongneung-dong, Seoul. Especially during busy evenings, stepping outside felt like meeting the whole neighborhood. The forest path had no franchises; all cafes, waffle shops, and doughnut places were small and unique. I sometimes miss the sense of stability I felt there.
I want to live somewhere I can walk endlessly or lie on the grass looking at the sky without driving far.</p>
<h2 id="hospitals">Hospitals</h2>
<p>While studying in Boston, my wisdom tooth decayed so badly my gums turned black. In pain, I finally booked an appointment with a Korean dentist. Desperate, I waited over a week for my visit. The dentist quickly checked my mouth and gave me two options:</p>
<ol>
<li>Get the tooth pulled and treated now. It would cost about $2,000 without insurance.</li>
<li>Take antibiotics and wait until I returned to Korea, where it would cost less than 10% of that.</li>
</ol>
<p>I chose the antibiotics and got all treatment in Korea two months later for just 30,000 won. That’s when I began to appreciate health insurance.
Many in Jeju travel to Seoul for medical care, often due to low trust in local hospitals like Jeju National University Hospital. While I hope to stay healthy, I don’t want to fly to hospitals for check-ups or surgeries. It doesn’t have to be right next door; a 1-2 hour train ride would be fine.</p>
<h2 id="culture">Culture</h2>
<p>“Where do you want to live?” is similar to “Who do you want to live with?” You can’t talk about desirable places without mentioning culture.
Some Korean friends moved to Canada or the U.S. saying they disliked Korean culture. Some were tired of a society dividing people by age, education, and neighborhoods; others wanted to escape a culture that dismisses and ostracizes those with different identities or values. While no place is perfectly rational and equal, these complaints are somewhat relatable.</p>
<p>I sometimes miss the U.S. because of the people. Four years after marrying, I visited and was surprised again by Americans who smiled when making eye contact (though generalizing about such a large country is impossible). Drivers who smiled and let you go first, neighbors who greeted you during walks, and people who apologized with “excuse me” for the slightest bump. These moments felt healing.</p>
<p>In contrast, seeing men urinating on the street, motorcycles blaring music, posters plastered everywhere, drunken people sprawled out, and people spitting made me feel suffocated. I want to live in a kind society where respect and consideration for neighbors come naturally.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practicing Being a Beginner</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/being-a-beginner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/being-a-beginner/</guid>
      <description>This is a translated version of Ko&amp;rsquo;s fourth essay of a series &amp;ldquo;Where Does the Courage to Take On Challenges Come From?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;In recent months, I’ve faced many fears. At a recent event, “Second Hand Books Station,” my partner and I reintroduced vegan sandwiches after a long time. Despite preparing all the ingredients beforehand, I had a sleepless night before the event. I was anxious about ruining the food and disappointing our customers.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This is a translated version of <a href="https://jagunbae.com/courage-4/">Ko&rsquo;s fourth essay</a> of a series &ldquo;Where Does the Courage to Take On Challenges Come From?&rdquo;</em></p>
<p><img src="https://jagunbae.com/content/images/size/w2000/2024/05/IMG_0256-1-.jpg" alt="Beginner driver sign"></p>
<p>In recent months, I’ve faced many fears. At a recent event, “Second Hand Books Station,” my partner and I reintroduced vegan sandwiches after a long time. Despite preparing all the ingredients beforehand, I had a sleepless night before the event. I was anxious about ruining the food and disappointing our customers. Why was I so scared of something I’d been making for a year and a half before closing my restaurant? Even small actions make me overthink sometimes.</p>
<p>This overthinking brings me to the theme of this letter. Like the saying that a motto is actually a pledge to remember what you’re not good at, I thought of the question, “Where does courage for challenges come from?” Not because I’m a master of challenges, but because I easily get intimidated by unfamiliar tasks. I envy those who stay composed in uncertain situations. I want to move forward with a light heart like them. To me, those who don’t feel anxious in unfamiliar situations are the most courageous people.</p>
<p>Reflecting on my past challenges, I realized I was always trembling with fear. In other words, I had the courage to throw myself into unknown situations despite the fear. Tasks that felt comfortable didn’t remain as challenges in my memory, no matter how difficult or successful they were.</p>
<p>Just as getting hit multiple times doesn’t stop it from hurting, summoning courage for challenges is always hard. Yet, some people decide to step into the ring, knowing it will hurt. They choose to take uncertain steps, even if change doesn’t feel entirely pleasant. These people make decisions as if they’ve never felt fear. They know how to handle their choices.</p>
<p>True courage isn’t a shield that protects us from anxiety in unfamiliar situations but the willingness to be committed to decisions despite knowing they’ll cause fear and anxiety. Because there are far more unknowns than knowns, we often become scared beginners. So, we must welcome the chances to be beginners again.</p>
<p>Of course, I’m still scared of what’s coming. I worry if I’ll do well and fear my efforts will go unnoticed. If someone like me tries to handle everything, I might get exhausted drifting between ideals and reality. So, I aspire to become someone who decides to act. Even at ninety, I want to be more excited than afraid of an unknown fruit, to walk a new path home, and to be okay with being a fool in front of new gadgets. I promise. I won’t stop practicing the mindset of becoming a beginner.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sharing a Sense of Stability</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/sense-of-stability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/sense-of-stability/</guid>
      <description>This is a translated version of Ko&amp;rsquo;s third essay of a series &amp;ldquo;Where Does the Courage to Take On Challenges Come From?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;If I were to write a new resume with “challenge” and “courage” as the criteria, the first line would boldly state: Founded the restaurant Cheesylazy. It was a reckless challenge for me and my partner. Since we had no experience, the long preparation period needed to open the restaurant really tested our courage.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This is a translated version of <a href="https://jagunbae.com/courage-3/">Ko&rsquo;s third essay</a> of a series &ldquo;Where Does the Courage to Take On Challenges Come From?&rdquo;</em></p>
<p><img src="https://kang.mataroa.blog/images/7eb7927f.jpeg" alt="Cheesylazy"></p>
<p>If I were to write a new resume with “challenge” and “courage” as the criteria, the first line would boldly state: <strong>Founded the restaurant Cheesylazy</strong>. It was a reckless challenge for me and my partner. Since we had no experience, the long preparation period needed to open the restaurant really tested our courage.</p>
<p>From graduating high school until I left my second job, I had never taken a break. My work and life revolved around short-term goals, each with a deadline. But opening a restaurant was an exception. I didn’t want to rush and present anything less than our best to the world. With a mindset of honing and polishing until I was satisfied, a year flew by. The time spent developing the menu and studying restaurant entrepreneurship was both challenging and a seemingly endless marathon.</p>
<p>Where did I find the courage to endure that time? Looking back, I’m genuinely curious. But the source of courage is often hiding in plain sight. For me, it was no different. Without my partner, husband, and best friend, Kang, I couldn’t have endured that uncertain period.</p>
<p>Some say that marriage makes you avoid risky choices due to added responsibility. But for me, it was the exact opposite. Kang brings out the truest version of myself. How much I earn in a month, what title I hold at which company—none of that mattered to Kang from the beginning. Kang listened to the voice of my heart, which even I had been ignoring. And of course, he treated himself the same way. If it wasn’t from his heart, he wouldn’t do it. His uncompromising personality slowly influenced me. Watching Kang, I thought, “I, too, can afford to be more reckless.”</p>
<p>Was Kang the only one like this? Fortunately, many people around me strive to understand the core of their hearts. For some, a hefty bank balance, financial support from parents, or a flawless career path might bring peace of mind. But in my case, the more people around me who truly understood me, the more I wanted to live recklessly in the way I believed was right.</p>
<p>The belief that I don’t need to persuade anyone. The attitude that it’s okay to live as myself. These feelings imprinted a sense of safety in my body and mind. If we look at reality alone, my future is more uncertain than ever. But I now feel a deeper sense of stability than ever, something that academic degrees, stable companies, or impressive titles could never guarantee.</p>
<p>I now strive not to judge the choices of those close to me. Sure, on some days, I think, “Isn’t that a bit inefficient? This way might be better,” or “Is that really the best choice?” But I suppress these thoughts and offer only genuine support. From experience, I know that some people, despite having full support from those around them, lose the fight with themselves and give up taking a step forward. In uncertain situations, even one lukewarm response can cause a person’s resolve to crumble.</p>
<p>We all struggle in our own ways to make better decisions, handle moments of choice, and endure anxiety. If I have a responsibility to the person I love, it&rsquo;s not to impose my thoughts as the &ldquo;right&rdquo; way, but to stand as solid support so they can stay true to themselves.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Standing at the Crossroads of “Should I or Shouldn’t I”</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/crossroads/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/crossroads/</guid>
      <description>This is a translated version of Ko&amp;rsquo;s second essay of a series &amp;ldquo;Where Does the Courage to Take On Challenges Come From?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;A Collection of Bold Challenges Happily Becoming a Fool In 2016, during my senior year of college, an interesting project appeared in my department’s Facebook group. It was a hackathon where I’d team up with exchange students from France and Germany to create a simple game in three days.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This is a translated version of <a href="https://jagunbae.com/courage-2/">Ko&rsquo;s second essay</a> of a series &ldquo;Where Does the Courage to Take On Challenges Come From?&rdquo;</em></p>
<p><img src="https://jagunbae.com/content/images/size/w2000/2024/04/IMG_1182_Original.webp" alt="Ko in 2016"></p>
<h2 id="a-collection-of-bold-challenges">A Collection of Bold Challenges</h2>
<h3 id="happily-becoming-a-fool">Happily Becoming a Fool</h3>
<p>In 2016, during my senior year of college, an interesting project appeared in my department’s Facebook group. It was a hackathon where I’d team up with exchange students from France and Germany to create a simple game in three days. As someone captivated by game development through consecutive semesters of related courses, I knew I had to be part of the event. But there was one problem: I had severe English anxiety. This hesitation lasted until the application deadline.</p>
<p>I thought sending the application would bring relief, but instead, my worries intensified. I had nightmares about being mocked for my poor English. During the day, I debated calling the department office to cancel my application. Then I convinced myself, &ldquo;Let’s just be a fool for three days. What’s the big deal?&rdquo; With this mindset, I joined the program.</p>
<p>Handling everything in English was harder than I imagined. I didn&rsquo;t understand half of what my friends said and sometimes lacked the courage to ask for clarification. But no major issues arose. No one made fun of me for struggling with English. Most importantly, I realized that being a fool wasn’t as shameful as I had feared.</p>
<h3 id="quitting-a-job-after-two-weeks">Quitting a Job After Two Weeks</h3>
<p>In the summer of 2017, after the job-hunting period, I started working on a large corporation’s new business team. The team’s culture and tasks were far from what I had envisioned. Each day of forced attendance felt like a waste of time. I began to regret not applying to a different company I had considered months earlier. It was a startup in my favorite field, but I didn’t apply because the company seemed too nascent.</p>
<p>I visited their website and realized I could still submit my resume and portfolio. However, I thought of my parents’ joy when they heard I got the job. None of my college friends had taken paths other than large corporations, media companies, law school, civil service exams, or graduate school. &ldquo;Am I the only one straying from the norm? What if I regret leaving this company after all the hard work to get here?&rdquo;</p>
<p>After several sleepless nights, I emailed the small company. Eventually, the startup marked the beginning of my career. Despite having only three colleagues, an uncertain future, and a low salary, I felt a sense of fulfillment from making a choice that suited me.</p>
<h3 id="lessons-from-compiling-my-bold-challenges">Lessons from Compiling My Bold Challenges</h3>
<p>Looking back at my past through the lens of “courage” was a first for me. The experiences I gathered don’t typically come up when I introduce myself, so they felt unfamiliar. However, I realized this collection of somewhat awkward and foolish challenges might show my true self better than a resume.</p>
<p>Many memories came flooding back beyond the two written here. It seems I fear: 1. exposing my vulnerabilities, 2. straying from the expected path, and 3. facing uncontrollable uncertainties. Many people have likely stood at the crossroads of “Should I or shouldn’t I” for similar reasons. So, what decision makes a person courageous? What was the right choice for me?</p>
<p>Honestly, it wouldn’t have mattered what decision I made. Whether my 24-year-old self backed out of the program due to English anxiety or my 25-year-old self stuck with the big company, the effort I put into moving forward despite my fears would remain the same. It wasn’t the decisions themselves but the struggle between fear and courage that transformed me.</p>
<p>So, it’s okay if you choose to stick to the familiar path after much deliberation. Even if the result of your courage seems trivial or doesn’t meet societal standards, it’s fine. Facing your fears and making decisions without avoiding them is already brave. Even if it doesn’t lead to visible changes or significant achievements, I call the inner battle with fear and anxiety a “challenge.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Deserve Leaders Who Help Others Grow</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/leaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/leaders/</guid>
      <description>Politicians are fighting again. I’m tired of seeing feeds full of arguments, not discussions. Politicians should care about the well-being of millions, but it seems like only the individualistic and power-hungry have succeeded in elections.&#xA;In Korea, citizens become hopeful when new politicians get elected. Like watching Korea vs. Brazil in the World Cup, most know there’s no chance of winning, but they still hope for a miracle. The same disappointment happens in politics.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Politicians are fighting again. I’m tired of seeing feeds full of arguments, not discussions. Politicians should care about the well-being of millions, but it seems like only the individualistic and power-hungry have succeeded in elections.</p>
<p>In Korea, citizens become hopeful when new politicians get elected. Like watching Korea vs. Brazil in the World Cup, most know there’s no chance of winning, but they still hope for a miracle. The same disappointment happens in politics. People get excited when politicians make rosy promises but get disappointed when they spend all their energy crushing others by any means necessary.</p>
<p>I haven’t seen a politician devoted to solving problems. Maybe the ones doing their jobs aren’t on the news. The quiet ones get forgotten, while the rowdy ones get remembered for the next election. In the end, citizens crave more content, not improvements.</p>
<p>Few believe officials, especially the president, are telling the truth. News has become entertainment. People prefer hearing about gossip and messiahs over multifaceted explanations.</p>
<p>Elections occur, but the candidates are almost always old men who don’t even know how to code “Hello World.” Korean students endure brutal exams for a chance to study in Seoul, but politicians aren’t tested for their suitability to lead the nation. I have nothing to say if some kid asks if there is anything to learn from our presidents. I can only say they are the most hated in the country.</p>
<p>We deserve better, but some kind of magic fools us again. We repeatedly elect another corrupt and egotistical maniac. Again, I dream of voting for leaders who understand their roles as uplifting others and serving the community.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making a Brave Decision Without Courage</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/brave-decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/brave-decision/</guid>
      <description>This is a translated version of Ko&amp;rsquo;s first essay of a series &amp;ldquo;Where Does the Courage to Take On Challenges Come From?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The last week of running our restaurant, Cheesylazy, was one of the most intense moments of my life. I fondly remember the farewells with customers, but one conversation stands out. A customer said, “You are really brave.” It was encouragement from a regular who had read our announcement that we were closing the restaurant to start a publishing company.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This is a translated version of <a href="https://jagunbae.com/courage-1/">Ko&rsquo;s first essay</a> of a series &ldquo;Where Does the Courage to Take On Challenges Come From?&rdquo;</em></p>
<p><img src="https://jagunbae.com/content/images/size/w2000/2024/04/IMG_8346.webp" alt="From Cheesylazy to Jagunbae"></p>
<p>The last week of running our restaurant, Cheesylazy, was one of the most intense moments of my life. I fondly remember the farewells with customers, but one conversation stands out. A customer said, “You are really brave.” It was encouragement from a regular who had read our announcement that we were closing the restaurant to start a publishing company.</p>
<p>I was grateful that someone who had watched our restaurant grow understood and supported our choice. However, I couldn’t react properly. Despite my 18 months of experience serving customers, I was still clumsy and terrified of the future. The word ‘brave’ felt very unfamiliar to me.</p>
<p>Up until three days before we announced the closure, I would wake up in the morning, terrified of what lay ahead, and cry. Even after naps, delicious food, and talking with my spouse, my anxiety didn’t subside. One day, two days, and three days. The persistent anxiety and depression felt new and alarming.</p>
<p>While writing this, I pulled out a note I wrote back then to organize my thoughts. It was a Q&amp;A to comfort myself, titled ‘Why My Mind is Dizzy Right Now.’</p>





<pre tabindex="0"><code>Why My Mind is Dizzy Right Now

1. Am I afraid I won’t do well?
2. Am I sad to leave Cheesylazy?
3. Do I not know what to do right now?
4. Do I not know how to explain what I need to do next?
5. Does no one understand my worries and pain?</code></pre><p>As I sobbed and wrote the note, I clearly saw the fear rooted deep inside me. At the same time, I realized how much I loved Cheesylazy. I wondered if it was okay to quit something I loved so much. Even while replying to messages from customers who saw the closure notice, I feared I might regret this decision one day. When one customer held my hand tightly and tearfully expressed her sadness, I even felt certain I was making the wrong decision. I secretly imagined taking back the closure notice, thinking, ‘Wouldn’t it be ridiculous if I said it was just a joke?’</p>
<p>My dictionary defines courage as ‘a fearless spirit.’ The spirit here must also be ‘vigorous and resolute.’ Was my decision wrong? Could I take responsibility for the uncertainties ahead? At that time, I was clearly terrified and neither vigorous nor resolute. The word ‘brave’ felt like an embarrassing compliment. I often reflected on the customer’s words that were neither swallowed with thanks nor denied.</p>
<p>Is it possible to make a courageous decision without courage? It might sound like wordplay, but that’s how I was back then. Shaking like a person without a shred of courage, yet making a brave decision. Was I a brave person for that? Or was I not brave because I was scared even after making the necessary decision? What is courage? Where does the courage to take on challenges come from? Will I still be a brave person, taking on challenges, even at eighty?</p>
<p>One interesting fact is that the ‘future’ I was so afraid of is now my ‘reality.’ I quickly adapted to my new work, and I’ve been so busy that I hardly have time to think about uncertainties or regrets. Though I was terrified just four months ago, it feels like a distant past.</p>
<p>Like a student reluctantly elected as class president but ends up fulfilling the role well by the end of the semester, sticking to brave choices seems to have made me somewhat braver. In hindsight, there’s not much courage can do for someone so brave that they handle everything effortlessly. The true power of courage might be a privilege enjoyed only by those who can make brave decisions despite lacking courage.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Write a Letter of Reconciliation</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/a-letter-of-reconciliation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/a-letter-of-reconciliation/</guid>
      <description>This is a translated version of Ko&amp;rsquo;s third essay of a series &amp;ldquo;How Can I Stop Being Angry?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Reason for Writing this Letter Hello Kang, it&amp;rsquo;s Ko. It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time since I&amp;rsquo;ve written a letter on a day that isn&amp;rsquo;t a birthday or anniversary. Honestly, I can hardly remember the last time I wrote a letter after getting married&amp;hellip; Hehe.&#xA;This is a letter of reconciliation that I&amp;rsquo;m sending to you.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This is a translated version of <a href="https://jagunbae.com/anger-3/">Ko&rsquo;s third essay</a> of a series &ldquo;How Can I Stop Being Angry?&rdquo;</em></p>
<p><img src="https://jagunbae.com/content/images/size/w2000/2024/03/KakaoTalk_Photo_2024-03-09-23-27-03.webp" alt="Kang and Ko"></p>
<h2 id="reason-for-writing-this-letter">Reason for Writing this Letter</h2>
<p><em>Hello Kang, it&rsquo;s Ko. It&rsquo;s been a long time since I&rsquo;ve written a letter on a day that isn&rsquo;t a birthday or anniversary. Honestly, I can hardly remember the last time I wrote a letter after getting married&hellip; Hehe.</em></p>
<p>This is a letter of reconciliation that I&rsquo;m sending to you. As you know, when I get angry, I can&rsquo;t control myself and I end up saying hurtful things. Even after we reconcile and things get better between us, I find myself dwelling on those moments of conflict. The angry tone of my voice, the selfishness in choosing words that I knew would hurt you. Each time, I end up hating myself and worrying that I cannot grow as a person.</p>
<p>I want to ask for your help. Help me to manage my anger better, to share good feelings with you going forward. That&rsquo;s why I&rsquo;m writing this letter of reconciliation today.</p>
<h2 id="its-more-than-who-is-right-or-wrong">It’s More Than Who Is Right or Wrong</h2>
<p>There&rsquo;s something more important than figuring out who was right or wrong. This letter is about resolving negative feelings and building a positive relationship. It&rsquo;s about committing to care for each other&rsquo;s hearts and actually finding ways to do so. Protecting our relationship is all that really matters to me, and I want to make that clear to you.</p>
<h2 id="praise-gratitude-respect">Praise, Gratitude, Respect</h2>
<p>We haven&rsquo;t fought recently and our relationship is stable. It might seem strange to write a letter of reconciliation when there&rsquo;s nothing to apologize for. But that&rsquo;s exactly why I thought now was the right time. When there&rsquo;s no one seeking forgiveness, we can talk on equal footing. I wanted to focus on communication, not apologies, and I hoped this letter of reconciliation would be a good starting point.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Nothing is impossible when the door of communication is open,&rdquo; as Thich Nhat Hanh says. How can I open your heart then? I thought about the words I hoped to hear from you — the words that signify praise, gratitude, and respect.</p>
<p>As I listed all of your praises, your traits I&rsquo;ve always wanted to emulate, and the coolness you possess that I lack, I realized why it hurts so much to argue with you. It&rsquo;s because I&rsquo;m afraid of losing someone as precious as you. Just writing down how much I love and respect you made me instantly happier.</p>
<h2 id="when-im-angry">When I&rsquo;m Angry</h2>
<p>*Why did I act that way towards someone as precious as you? I regretted the words too easily after saying them.</p>
<p>Looking back, I always thought there was a logical reason for my anger. I believed I had the right to be angry, and I thought you should apologize first. Seeing you unaware of my frustration made me even angrier. Can you see how narrow-minded I can become when I&rsquo;m angry?*</p>
<p>I chose to write a letter because I thought it was necessary to carefully convey my views before having a real-time conversation. Instead of guessing what&rsquo;s on your mind, I wanted to focus on organizing my thoughts. I felt it was more appropriate to share how I felt instead of pointing out the actions of yours that upset me.</p>
<p>As I tried to objectively reflect on myself, I wrote in detail what happened inside me when I got angry. Just as I can&rsquo;t immediately understand your actions and words during a fight, the same must be true for you. If we ever face a situation where we&rsquo;re both upset, I want you to know it&rsquo;s never because I despise you.</p>
<h2 id="promises-and-asking-for-help">Promises and Asking for Help</h2>
<p>I decided not to take the easy way out with a vague promise of mutual forgiveness. I dislike the idea of shamelessly asking you to just understand my feelings. What I need is not just a promise, but real guidelines for practical actions. To convey my strong desire to change, I needed to be specific and clear about what I&rsquo;m asking for.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ll try not to lash out with expressions like ‘You are annoying&rsquo; or ‘You piss me off&rsquo;. Lightening my words seems to help dissipate the anger more quickly. So, I thought about using &lsquo;I feel neglected&rsquo;. Doesn&rsquo;t that sound better? From now on, if I say &lsquo;I feel neglected&rsquo;, please try to understand why I feel that way. Just doing that will make me feel a lot better.</p>
<p>It seems there&rsquo;s a law of conservation of anger. If I keep suppressing it, it will eventually explode. Instead of holding it in until a big fight, what if we let it loose little by little? Smaller bouts of anger are easier to handle. If it seems like I&rsquo;m getting angry over trivial things, maybe I&rsquo;m trying hard not to turn this moment into a big fight. I&rsquo;ll try to calm my anger this way.</p>
<h2 id="reply-i-want-to-hear">Reply I Want to Hear</h2>
<p>In a previous letter, I wrote that we should be able to openly discuss our strategies to handle heated arguments. Fighting isn&rsquo;t a solo act. So, you and I both need to be in the same boat. This letter of reconciliation is just a starting point. If you, like me, decide to write a letter of reconciliation, you should be able to ask for a reply. Act boldly. Ask for a chance to enlighten each other.</p>
<p>*I&rsquo;m curious if you are willing to join the promise of reconciliation. I want to hear about what goes on inside your mind when you&rsquo;re angry, and if there&rsquo;s anything unsaid about our past fights.</p>
<p>If it&rsquo;s okay, could you write me a reply? We can also reserve a time to talk about this. Either way, I&rsquo;ll always be waiting to hear your story.*</p>
<h2 id="lets-write-a-letter-of-reconciliation">Let&rsquo;s Write a Letter of Reconciliation</h2>
<p>&lsquo;I don&rsquo;t want to be angry with you, my love. So please help me!’ Maybe conveying this simple message is all there is to reconciliation. If the other person truly cares, they&rsquo;ll take your hand and start listening. Even if you&rsquo;re ignored, or if you can&rsquo;t deliver the letter, that&rsquo;s okay. When writing this letter of reconciliation, you may notice the knots of anger loosen a bit. Forgiving and reconciling with yourself is more important than the other one’s acknowledgement. In that sense, I&rsquo;ve already achieved my goal.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I’ve Helped 17 People Ditch Naver Blog and Start Personal Blogging</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/workshops/</guid>
      <description>In South Korea, most bloggers use Naver Blog to publish their writings.1 The indie blogging culture is almost nonexistant. If you say &amp;ldquo;I blog&amp;rdquo; in this country, most people would assume you are writing on Naver Blog.&#xA;Although Naver Blog is infamous for its overwhelming amount of bot-generated-crappy-sponsored-SEO content, most writers still stay on Naver Blog because they simply are not aware of another option. Naver also makes sure only the content stamped &amp;ldquo;Naver&amp;rdquo; rank high in its search results.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://jagunbae.com/content/images/size/w1600/2024/04/KakaoTalk_Photo_2024-04-04-06-33-16-008.jpeg" alt="1:1 blogging session"></p>
<p>In South Korea, most bloggers use Naver Blog to publish their writings.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> The indie blogging culture is almost nonexistant. If you say &ldquo;I blog&rdquo; in this country, most people would assume you are writing on Naver Blog.</p>
<p>Although Naver Blog is infamous for its overwhelming amount of bot-generated-crappy-sponsored-SEO content, most writers still stay on Naver Blog because they simply are not aware of another option. Naver also makes sure only the content stamped &ldquo;Naver&rdquo; rank high in its search results. So for Korean bloggers, migrating to another platform or publishing on a custom domain could lead to giving up a shit ton of traffic.</p>
<p>I wanted to challenge this Naver-ruled bloggging landscape. I&rsquo;m no web developer, but I could explain how to buy a domain, choose a platform, write in Markdown, and use an RSS feed reader. Some of my friends had asked me to teach them how to start a blog like <a href="https://kangminsuk.com">mine</a>, so I knew there was a demand for my skills. I had alreay spent hundreds of hours building and polishing my blog, so I felt confident to prepare for a personal blogging workshop. I was excited to build a new community of writers.</p>
<h2 id="the-first-workshop">The First Workshop</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;ve hosted three &ldquo;Let&rsquo;s Start a Personal Blog&rdquo; workshops in my office this year. The first workshop was in January. There were seven people, including me, and I taught how to purchase a domain, create a blog, and write in Markdown all within two hours.</p>
<p>No need to open a code editor or terminal. I tried to make the first workshop as easygoing as possible without the need for any programming knowledge. The workshop was about online writing, not web development.</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s how the workshop went:</p>
<ol>
<li>Talked about what developers care about when building &ldquo;a perfect website&rdquo;. I showed <a href="http://motherfuckingwebsite.com/">Motherfucking Website</a> series like <a href="http://bettermotherfuckingwebsite.com">this one</a>, <a href="https://thebestmotherfucking.website">this one</a>, and <a href="https://perfectmotherfuckingwebsite.com">this one</a>.</li>
<li>Bought domains on <a href="https://porkbun.com">Porkbun</a>.</li>
<li>Signed up for accounts on <a href="https://mataroa.blog">Mataroa</a>.</li>
<li>Connected custom domains on Mataroa and practiced how to publish posts and pages, manage images, and use a feature like theme, newsletter, and comment.</li>
<li>Practiced how to write in Markdown. Introduced Markdown editors like <a href="https://github.com/MarkEdit-app/MarkEdit">MarkEdit</a> and <a href="https://www.marktext.cc">MarkText</a>.</li>
<li>Subscribed to each other&rsquo;s blog using a RSS feed reader like <a href="https://mire.meadowing.club">Mire</a>, <a href="https://github.com/parksb/collie">Collie</a>, <a href="https://netnewswire.com">NetNewsWire</a>, and <a href="https://www.commafeed.com/#/app/category/all">CommaFeed</a>. I intentionally introduced free &amp; minimal feed readers.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="the-second-workshop">The Second Workshop</h2>
<p>The second workshop happened a month after the first one. I had to make a few changes to improve our meeting:</p>
<ol>
<li>Two hours was not enough to talk about everything I knew about personal blogging. In addition, the participants wanted to have a longer chat with each other. I couldn&rsquo;t provide enough time to discuss each other&rsquo;s domain name and writing topics. To make sure there&rsquo;s enough time to share knowledge and network with fellow bloggers, I extended the workshop to two separate meetings. Once a week, six people met in the office for two hours.</li>
<li>All members of the first workshop were satisfied with Mataroa, but I wanted to introduce more blogging platforms for the second workshop. So I provided four different options: Mataroa, <a href="https://bearblog.dev">Bear Blog</a>, <a href="https://pika.page">Pika</a>, and <a href="https://smol.pub">Smol Pub</a>. In the end, two chose Mataroa, one chose Bear Blog, and one chose Pika.</li>
</ol>
<p>I loved our conversations about domain names, website designs, and the differences between the four platforms. However, I also realized meeting twice to create a minimalist blog could feel a little time-wasting to some people.</p>
<h2 id="the-third-workshop">The Third Workshop</h2>
<p><img src="https://jagunbae.com/content/images/2024/04/KakaoTalk_Photo_2024-04-04-06-33-16-003.webp" alt="1:1 blogging session"></p>
<p>The third one was held during &ldquo;<a href="https://jagunbae.com/stopbooks2-review/">The Stop for Readers</a>,&rdquo; which was a mini festival filled with 19 different bookstores selling already-read books.</p>
<p>I was in charge of a program called &ldquo;30-minute Instant Blog.&rdquo; For two days, I met 7 people 1:1 to tailor-make a personal blog. I worked with the participants to look for a perfect domain name on <a href="https://domaintyper.com">DomainTyper</a>, choose between Mataroa and Bear Blog, and write on a Markdown editor. Although I promised 30 minutes, I spent around 50 minutes per session. Signing up and paying for the domain and platform took more than I expected.</p>
<h2 id="what-i-learned">What I Learned</h2>
<p>So far, I&rsquo;ve helped 17 people create personal blogs. I compiled <a href="https://blogs.jagunbae.com">16 of the RSS feeds on my website</a> if you&rsquo;re interested in checking them out(all blogs are in Korean of course).</p>
<p>Last, I&rsquo;d like to share some lessons from the three workshops:</p>
<ol>
<li>Everyone agreed writing on profit-driven corporate platforms sucks so much ass. I tried, especially during the first two workshops, to explain why I think it&rsquo;s crucial to own one&rsquo;s data. Most participants expressed gratitudes for indie platforms like Mataroa because they finally could focus on writing instead of catering to algorithmic ranking and placing ad banners. Online writing is much more fun on the platforms made for writers, not users. I also tried to make sure that it was important to pay for great softwares to support developers.</li>
<li>Most of the members had never purchased a domain name. Once again, I realized a simple task like buying a domain name could sound like a huge barrier. Everyone was surprised how easy it was to set up a DNS record. Thanks to amazing tools, building on the Internet has become so easy, but many of us still wait for big tech companies to upgrade features and solve problems. No one had heard of Markdown, RSS, and alternative blogging platforms either.</li>
<li>After building a blog together, some writers still have not published their first post. I don&rsquo;t blame them, but I wonder if there was anything I could do to help building writing habits.</li>
</ol>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Naver is a dominant tech conglomerate in South Korea. It is commonly referred to as &ldquo;Google of Korea.&rdquo;&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fighting Is Not Something You Do Alone</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/fighting-is-not-something-you-do-alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/fighting-is-not-something-you-do-alone/</guid>
      <description>This is a translated version of Ko&amp;rsquo;s second essay of a series &amp;ldquo;How Can I Stop Being Angry?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;I think about being married to you, and that woman is a stranger to me.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I have to know you forever!&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Everyday I wake up and I hope you&amp;rsquo;re dead &amp;hellip; Get hit by a car and die!&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry. These are not my words to Kang; they are lines from the movie &amp;ldquo;Marriage Story.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This is a translated version of <a href="https://jagunbae.com/anger-2/">Ko&rsquo;s second essay</a> of a series &ldquo;How Can I Stop Being Angry?&rdquo;</em></p>
<p><img src="https://jagunbae.com/content/images/size/w2000/2024/03/E7F2DE17-D6C3-49C2-BE29-F6B4ACD45E0D-473-00000085D2642488.webp" alt="marriage-story"></p>
<p>&ldquo;I think about being married to you, and that woman is a stranger to me.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;I can&rsquo;t believe I have to know you forever!&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;Everyday I wake up and I hope you&rsquo;re dead &hellip; Get hit by a car and die!&rdquo;</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t worry. These are not my words to Kang; they are lines from the movie &ldquo;Marriage Story.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s one of my favorite films, and this scene is my absolute favorite within it. The protagonists, Charlie and Nicole, are in the midst of a custody battle during their divorce proceedings. Exhausted by the slander about each other conveyed by their lawyers, Nicole visits Charlie&rsquo;s house to communicate directly with him, but things don&rsquo;t go as expected. They both want to resolve things peacefully without escalating the lawsuit further. However, as the conversation progresses, anger starts to surface bit by bit. The conversation turns into a competition of &lsquo;who can hurt another more.&rsquo; The exploding emotions were so agonizing that even I, as a viewer, felt suffocated by the intensity.</p>
<p>Of course, I don&rsquo;t particularly favor this scene for some perverted reason like taking pleasure in cruel emotional fights. Charlie, collapsing on the floor in tears, embraces Nicole&rsquo;s legs and says, &ldquo;I&rsquo;m sorry.&rdquo; Nicole strokes Charlie&rsquo;s back and replies, &ldquo;I&rsquo;m sorry too.&rdquo; At the start of their conversation, they sit far apart in a small room, but by the end of their fight, they are huddled together in the middle of the room. The narrowed distance between them. The feeling of loving and hating someone so much. I hoped they wouldn&rsquo;t part ways. I understood why this movie was titled &ldquo;Marriage Story&rdquo; instead of &ldquo;Divorce Story.&rdquo;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;When the door of communication is open, there is nothing we cannot do. Therefore, we must always strive to keep that door open.&rdquo; - Thich Nhat Hanh, &ldquo;Anger&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Leaning onto each other and sharing the pain in their hearts, what the two needed wasn&rsquo;t a long heated fight but a brief moment of understanding. I wondered, is there any way to take the step of reconciliation before getting angry? If only that were possible, there would be no need to say terrible things to the person you love. There wouldn&rsquo;t even be anger in our heart or broken relationships in the first place. Why do we have to let out intense anger to barely understand each other?</p>
<p>When I don&rsquo;t know how to express anger properly, I end up getting angrier than necessary. Saying things like &ldquo;What&rsquo;s wrong? Just say it!&rdquo; only escalates anger, and friends who have no idea why I&rsquo;m angry often lead to more frustration. The more precious the other person is, the faster that anger amplifies. &ldquo;How can someone who claims to love me not understand how I feel?&rdquo; One person&rsquo;s anger soon becomes two people&rsquo;s, and that anger evolves into a fight.</p>
<p>I can&rsquo;t just choose to talk to people whose styles match well with mine. In family relationships, I have to put in even more effort to align my attitudes toward anger. But no one has taught me how to express anger well to someone I love. I could only guess. <em>Saying this hurts the other person more. That person reacts this way when angry. The fight didn&rsquo;t escalate when I walked away.</em> Making mistakes, going through trial and error, figuring it out intuitively. This has been my way of learning anger management.</p>
<p>When issues arise at work, we hold meetings to resolve them. But even though I believe dealing with emotions like anger is an important issue, I couldn&rsquo;t bring myself to put this problem on the discussion table. As a result, I had to go through costly failures. Sometimes my words about the other person&rsquo;s feelings fueled their anger. I would also get upset when no one appreciated my efforts to hold back the anger. As I went through this trial and error, my heart was slowly falliing apart.</p>
<p>If I can&rsquo;t learn by direct experience or adept <em>noonchi</em>, there was only one option left: asking directly. Of course, I can&rsquo;t discuss strategies for peace while seething with anger. Just as a healthy person can imagine death more objectively than a sick person can, I thought now, when things are good between me and Kang, is the best timing to talk about anger. I worried that bringing up past fights might ruin a good day or make it seem like dredging up old conflicts unnecessarily. But I knew safeguarding the loved one from anger was more important than my pride.</p>
<p>Fighting is not something you do alone. So figuring out how to express and deal with anger is not something to be done alone either. &ldquo;What can I do to help when you&rsquo;re angry?&rdquo; &ldquo;I need time alone when I&rsquo;m angry.&rdquo; &ldquo;I was always grateful for how you tried to understand my feelings even when I was angry.&rdquo; Before anger claws at us once again, I wanted to convey my feelings directly to Kang. After much thought, I decided to write Kang a &ldquo;Letter of Reconciliation&rdquo;. Hoping my efforts would reverse the order of fighting and reconciling.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Express the will to seek peace with others. Ask for help. - Thich Nhat Hanh, &ldquo;Anger&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“People Can’t be Fixed&#34;</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/people-cant-be-fixed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/people-cant-be-fixed/</guid>
      <description>This is a translated version of Ko&amp;rsquo;s first essay of a series &amp;ldquo;How Can I Stop Being Angry?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;I can&amp;rsquo;t remember why I was angry. The beginning was probably trivial. For example, Kang forgot to clean the sink after washing dishes, did not leave the bowl in its place, or responded insignificantly to my idea. When Kang and I decided to start a restaurant together, we quarreled like never before. The same thing happened that day.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This is a translated version of <a href="https://jagunbae.com/anger-1/">Ko&rsquo;s first essay</a> of a series &ldquo;How Can I Stop Being Angry?&rdquo;</em></p>
<p><img src="https://jagunbae.com/content/images/size/w2000/2024/02/----.webp" alt="kang_and_ko"></p>
<p>I can&rsquo;t remember why I was angry. The beginning was probably trivial. For example, Kang forgot to clean the sink after washing dishes, did not leave the bowl in its place, or responded insignificantly to my idea. When Kang and I decided to start a restaurant together, we quarreled like never before. The same thing happened that day. The argument was exacerbated off guard while we prepared for the dinner business.</p>
<p>Even those who know us well would see the angry couple and ask, &ldquo;Who are they?&rdquo; Angry Kang behaves like &ldquo;a taciturn high school student.&rdquo; He shuts his mouth tightly because he doesn&rsquo;t want to raise his voice. He also puts a sign signaling his anger and waits for the counterpart to acknowledge his feelings. He needs attention but hates nagging. On the other hand, when I&rsquo;m angry, I transform into &ldquo;a father who thinks he knows everything about his child.&rdquo; I hold tightly to a set of personal rules. I talk to the other person as if I&rsquo;m listening, but if the conversation doesn&rsquo;t flow as I please, my face crumples.</p>
<p>It was a fight between &ldquo;a taciturn high school student&rdquo; and &ldquo;a father who thinks he knows everything about his children.” Eventually, I was the one who burst with uncontrollable anger. That&rsquo;s why I often felt unfair. After the meaningless quibble, all I had left was the regretful words I spit out. It didn&rsquo;t matter what the cause was. I crossed the line and hurt my husband. The aftermath of my anger was too much to handle. I was too much of a foolish fighter to claim, &ldquo;I&rsquo;m sorry I was angry. But you did it wrong, too!&rdquo;</p>
<p>The same fight repeated that day. My anger spread similarly, but I made two unforgettable mistakes. The first is that I cursed at my husband. Oh, I&rsquo;m so embarrassed to talk about this. But at that moment, I couldn&rsquo;t even think my action would be reprehensible. It was like standing amid a furious fire. I didn’t care about Kang’s feelings. My head spun faster than ever to pick out words to attack him. The second is that one more person was standing beside us. My dad, who stopped by our restaurant to grab a cup of coffee as usual, had to watch the live broadcast of our emotional shitshow. Of course, Kang wanted to stop the fight as soon as he saw my father, but I continued to lash out at Kang. My dad must have been sad to witness his daughter and son-in-law bickering with each other like the worst enemies. More importantly, how humiliating must it have been for my husband to show unconstrained rage to his father-in-law?</p>
<p>Eventually, my father left the space in bewilderment, and Kang soon walked out of the store as well. I was alone for the dinner service. As the anger began to subside little by little, I felt regret, guilt, and shame. I wish I could run home and apologize immediately, but I had to stay and finish the business. All I could do was self-reflection. Kang is the person I want to protect the most. Kang is more important than anything else, so I want to keep him safe from harmful elements. I sometimes joke that I want to protect him in a large transparent hamster ball. I couldn&rsquo;t believe I had hurt the most precious person like I&rsquo;d never done before. It was impossible to understand. &lsquo;Why did I get so angry at my husband?&rsquo;</p>
<p>I couldn&rsquo;t let go and stay the same. I obviously had a problem. As a human in the 21st century, I opened a YouTube app and searched &ldquo;How to hold back my anger.&rdquo; Watching the endless results, I got a strange comfort from the fact that there were so many hot-tempered people like me. Psychologists in the videos explained some tips to cool down, but people in the comment sections seemed to have different ideas. &ldquo;Those who are short-tempered will never change,” “People can never be fixed,” and “If your partner gets angry easily, you really should break up with that person.”</p>
<p>Then I came across a video. Like me, the man in the video had difficulty dealing with anger at his family. His wife asked a serious question that challenged his attitude towards invariable wrath. &ldquo;Can you be angry at ABC like you did to me?” (ABC was a close friend he had known for a long time. ABC was like his older brother, so the husband always paid respect to ABC). After hearing the question, the man concluded he would not be able to get angry at ABC. That’s when I realized he and I were 100% capable of controlling our anger. We were actively choosing our targets.</p>
<p>I felt like I could take out my anger because the victim was a family. I automatically believed our strong relationship would withstand my outrage. I belittled the bond Kang and I had built over the years. Although the fact that I was ungrateful to my loved ones made me disappointed in myself, I also felt refreshed from fatigue. It was like hearing the exact name of my illness to discover there was a cure.</p>
<p>Anger is the same as fire in a Chinese character. Anger indeed spreads like wildfire. However, as the owner of my mind, I could always take a breath and calm my anger. If I could choose a person to get angry at, I should be able to root out the negative emotion. I must learn to prevent fire and put it out quickly when my heart is set aflame. Some say a person doesn&rsquo;t change, but I had to take back the initiative to lead my life again. I know what I want to do next. I want to protect the people I love.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Personal Branding Necessary for New Artists?</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/personal-branding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/personal-branding/</guid>
      <description>Is personal branding necessary for new artists? I can argue for both sides.&#xA;Yes. Art doesn&amp;rsquo;t get sold without marketing. We’ve seen too many influencers/celebrities becoming top-selling authors and painters. In this era of never-ending feeds of content, artists survive by standing out on TikTok, YouTube, Instagram, X, Threads, LinkedIn, Bluesky, or Mastodon. No. Artists must be dedicated to their crafts, not succumbing to profit-driven algorithms. ‘Likes’ and ‘followers’ cannot represent art’s true value.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Is personal branding necessary for new artists? I can argue for both sides.</p>
<ol>
<li>Yes. Art doesn&rsquo;t get sold without marketing. We’ve seen too many influencers/celebrities becoming top-selling authors and painters. In this era of never-ending feeds of content, artists survive by standing out on TikTok, YouTube, Instagram, X, Threads, LinkedIn, Bluesky, or Mastodon.</li>
<li>No. Artists must be dedicated to their crafts, not succumbing to profit-driven algorithms. ‘Likes’ and ‘followers’ cannot represent art’s true value. Chasing online fame is the wrong kind of game to play as an aspiring artist.</li>
</ol>
<p>So what should I do? This is a constant battle. I’m aware maintaining a sizable audience is crucial for many professional writers. On the other hand, checking analytics all day has robbed me of the focus I need for my actual job. I wonder if it’s possible to build meaningful relationships online without being part of a worldwide status game.</p>
<p>I thought joining a different kind of social media could be an answer to this conundrum. That’s why I’ve tried lots of indie platforms such as <a href="https://www.are.na">Are.na</a>, <a href="https://micro.blog/kang">Mirco.blog</a>, and <a href="https://sublime.app/kang">Sublime</a>. I admire these services because they offer subscription-based Internet town squares that show zero interest in spying on the members. However, in these communities, I still couldn’t forgo the desire to be seen. Even in the absence of ‘likes’ and ‘followers,’ I fell straight back to seeking attention and validation.</p>
<p>Now, I stopped using any social media. I’ve decided to put all my creative energy into publishing essays and short stories on my blog. I turned all analytics off to forget about data trends and dopamine hits. My strategy is to repeat the process of writing and publishing until I become confident in the craft of writing. Spending hours on platform shopping must end today.</p>
<p><a href="https://miniflux.app">My RSS feed reader</a> is my new social media. In fact, all of the authentic relationships I’ve built online were through blogs. I love exchanging emails with other bloggers because reading each other’s writing is really the best way to develop strong connections. Blogging could sound lonely and boring, but my readers know more about me than most of my offline friends. I have to remind myself that I’m here to make friends, not followers.</p>
<p>Here’s my conclusion. I’m not productizing myself or creating a personal brand. I don’t want to worry about selling before I have the skill set to be considered a writer. I won’t miss social media either. I’m happy with books and blogs on my hands.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You must stay drunk on writing so reality cannot destroy you. - Ray Bradbury</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Wrote Morning Pages for Two Weeks</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/morningpages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/morningpages/</guid>
      <description>I’ve had a sign over my typewriter for over 25 years now, which reads “Don’t think!” You must never think at the typewriter — you must feel. … The worst thing you do when you think is lie — you can make up reasons that are not true for the things that you did, and what you’re trying to do as a creative person is surprise yourself — find out who you really are, and try not to lie, try to tell the truth all the time.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>I’ve had a sign over my typewriter for over 25 years now, which reads “Don’t think!” You must never think at the typewriter — you must feel. … The worst thing you do when you think is lie — you can make up reasons that are not true for the things that you did, and what you’re trying to do as a creative person is surprise yourself — find out who you really are, and try not to lie, try to tell the truth all the time. - Ray Bradbury</p>
</blockquote>
<p>For two weeks, as soon as I woke up, I opened my laptop and wrote whatever came into my mind.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> Julia Cameron suggested filling three pages, but I didn’t want to let this routine be another form of homework. I just stopped whenever I felt like I was done after 20 to 30 minutes. Sometimes, I wrote more than three pages and sometimes only a few paragraphs.</p>
<p>I decided to give morning pages a try because I wanted to form a habit of writing without the fear of self-censorship and criticism. I didn’t want to be the adult who was once an artist as a child. I wished to cultivate the nonconformist spirit within me.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The amount of eccentricity in a society has generally been proportional to the amount of genius, mental vigour, and moral courage which it contained. That so few now dare to be eccentric, marks the chief danger of the time. - John Stuart Mill</p>
</blockquote>
<p>After two weeks, the impact was less than transformative. There was no enlightenment. My life was not magically charged with the sudden burst of creative energy. I still struggled to focus on a single project and often stared at the monitor lifelessly.</p>
<p>However, when I reread my journal, I realized what I wrote in the morning was worth revisiting. The sentences were not refined but seemed more authentic than my blog posts. Some ideas even inspired me to work on long-form writings.</p>
<p>Curious to have a peek? Here’s some snippets from my morning pages this week (never sharing my journal again):</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="monday">Monday</h2>
<ul>
<li>My wish is to be a great creator, teacher, and friend.</li>
<li>I’m using this tool called MarkEdit. It’s super fast. Crisp and simple. I’m thinking of using this to write for my blog posts in the future. The details of design matter right? Some apps just feel right. Feel like a breath of fresh air. Tastes like freedom almost. Why is that? Are we making a brand that makes people feel that way? &lsquo;Damn these guys are doing something different&rsquo; should be the first impression.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="tuesday">Tuesday</h2>
<ul>
<li>Do I need a purpose to wake up and jumpstart the day? Maybe. I do have tons of things I want to do, but they don’t feel urgent right now. Maybe that’s a problem. Maybe… Who knows?</li>
<li>I think in two languages. No, I mostly think in Korean. Maybe it’s because I mostly speak in Korean. It’s weird. I consume information in English, and I’m even writing this journal in English. But I’m surrounded by people speaking Korean.</li>
<li>So, what is creativity? What should I read about creativity? Originality may mean authenticity. Let’s dig into a bunch of interviews and see how other artists answer this question. What is creativity and how do they develop this skill? That’s really an interesting topic. Because creativity is definitely not about talent. It’s about constant work. Workworkwork. Just work tirelessly.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="wednesday">Wednesday</h2>
<p>My Input and Output</p>
<p>Current input:</p>
<ul>
<li>Books.</li>
<li>Blogs.</li>
<li>Conversations with wife, mom, and a few friends.</li>
<li>Podcasts.</li>
<li>TV shows and movies.</li>
<li>News.</li>
<li>Social media.</li>
</ul>
<p>Current output:</p>
<ul>
<li>Writings (newsletter, blog posts, and a book).</li>
<li>Podcast.</li>
<li>Workshops and meetings.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="thursday">Thursday</h2>
<ul>
<li>PIKA가 런칭했다. 퍼스널블로깅플랫폼이 많아지고 있다. 서로 뭐가 다를까 싶어도 놀랍게도 다른 매력이 있다. 기능이 아니라 보여지는 디자인이 얼마나 중요한지 새삼 깨닫는다. 우리는 어떤 디자인을 내세우고 있는가. 충분히 매력있나? 딱 봤을 때, 아 저 로고가 박힌 티셔츠를 입고 싶다고 느낄 수 있나.</li>
<li>창의적이다는 말은 사람 혹은 제품에 쓰인다. 새롭거나 쓰임이 있거나. 둘 중에 뭔가가 있어야 한다. 새롭다는 것은 무엇을 의미하는가. 완전히 새로운 발명이거나 아니면 새로운 접근이 필요하다. 창의적인 사람에 대하여 이야기 해보자. 창의적인 사람은 평범함에서 비범함을 발견한다. 봉준호는 창의적이다. 상상을 잘해서가 아니라 상상을 현실로 만들기 때문에 창의적이다. 나도 가끔 상상을 한다. 만약 외계인이 넘어와 인간을 지배한다면 어떻게 될까. 하루 아침에 피라미드 맨 위에서 바닥으로 내려오는 현실을 받아들일 수 있을까.</li>
<li>야 그 주제로 영화를 만들어봐, 소설을 써봐, 뭐라도 해봐는 할 수 있지만 실제로 스토리를 짜서 세상에 내놓고 감동을 줄 수 있는 능력이 있나. 그것이 창의성에 핵심이 아닐까. 하나에 집착한다. 그리고 이뤄낸다. 그것이 아마 창의성의 근본이다.</li>
<li>일주일 간 창의적인 사람이 되고자 노력했다. 이상하게 들리는 말이다. 창의성을 인공적으로 만들 수나 있을까. 어찌됐든 한번 발악했다.</li>
<li>나는 어떤 사람을 창의적인 사람으로 바라볼까. 나는 어떤 물건을 봤을 때 창의적이라 생각할까? 창의적인 사람을 찾기는 참 어렵다. 유행을 잘 따라가는 사람, 정해진 틀 안에서 경쟁을 잘하는 사람은 있지만 ‘아 저 사람 참 창의적이다’ 싶은 사람은 주변에 찾기 어렵다.</li>
<li>창의적인 사람을 세상에 없던 작품을 만든다. 완전히 새로울 필요는 없지만, 평범한 일상에 새로운 시각을 제시한다. 놀라움이 있다. 불편하게 한다.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="friday">Friday</h2>
<ul>
<li>How to survive as an artist? That’s a question that we all have to answer. I can teach, I can sell books, I can maybe become a professor.</li>
<li>I should try to care more about the people in this country. Great stuff is happening, and I might just be oblivious of it. Should I move to Seoul? Maybe I should. Should I try to be more connected to Seoul? Maybe I should.</li>
<li>Solitude. Just reading books and writing books. Just books and books and books.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>I’ll continue to jot down my stream of consciousness every morning. I don’t expect morning pages to be the secret sauce for my creative endeavors. I only know that my work will be more truthful if I’m aware of what I really care about. So far, rereading piles of private journals seems like the best way to learn about myself.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>I set up <a href="https://dabble.me">Dabble Me</a> to send me an email every morning. I wrote my morning page as a reply to the email so I didn’t need to worry about managing all the data. Writing on my desktop email app also helped me be more lighthearted. I could pretend like I was writing a letter to myself.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yes, I Am an Artist</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/artist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/artist/</guid>
      <description>The most important thing about art is to work. Nothing else matters except sitting down every day and trying. - Steven Pressfield&#xA;A friend called me &amp;ldquo;an artist.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;No, I&amp;rsquo;m not an artist.&amp;rdquo; I shook my head and hands immediately as a reflex.&#xA;Why did I refuse to be considered an artist? I can think of a few reasons.&#xA;My art is not generating money. My art is not famous.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>The most important thing about art is to work. Nothing else matters except sitting down every day and trying. - Steven Pressfield</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A friend called me &ldquo;an artist.&rdquo; &ldquo;No, I&rsquo;m not an artist.&rdquo; I shook my head and hands immediately as a reflex.</p>
<p>Why did I refuse to be considered an artist? I can think of a few reasons.</p>
<ol>
<li>My art is not generating money.</li>
<li>My art is not famous.</li>
<li>Thus, I&rsquo;m not confident in my creations.</li>
</ol>
<p>I never thought I was making art professionally. To me, only people like Picasso and Kendrick were ordained as artists. I knew I had a budding desire to craft more, but I never took myself seriously.</p>
<p>I glorified the outcome, not the process.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Living life as an artist is a practice. You are either engaging in the practice or you&rsquo;re not. It makes no sense to say you&rsquo;re not good at it. It&rsquo;s like saying, &ldquo;I&rsquo;m not good at being a monk.&rdquo; You are either living as a monk or you&rsquo;re not. - Rick Rubin</p>
</blockquote>
<p>My life is already filled with art. I write, record, and edit in the office until it&rsquo;s dark and quiet outside. No one forces me to sit and stare at the monitor, but I still adhere to my publication schedule. It&rsquo;s a plain fact; I&rsquo;m devoting my life to the art of storytelling.</p>
<p>I dig for inspiration when I consume other books, podcasts, and videos. I sometimes sigh when I encounter an exceptional sentence in a novel. <em>&lsquo;How can I write like this?&rsquo;</em> I get jealous of their God-given talent and worry about my embarrassing skills.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Art is not about thinking something up. It is about the opposite—getting something down. - Julia Cameron</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In the end, no one cares whether I&rsquo;m entitled to be an artist. There&rsquo;s no rush to tattoo &ldquo;artist&rdquo; in my bio. This inner conflict will be resolved after putting enough work in. I&rsquo;m the one who quit jobs and closed a restaurant to spend more time on art. I love being an artist and wish to stay truthful when a friend calls me so.</p>
<p>Over the next two weeks, I want to share my thoughts as I become even more invested in art-making. This will be a fun experiment. I hope to answer some questions as well.</p>
<ul>
<li>What is <em>creativity</em>?</li>
<li>How do I learn, express, and publish more?</li>
<li>What happens if I write morning pages every day?</li>
<li>Can I go back to being a child again?</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does the world need my books?</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/does-the-world-need-more-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/does-the-world-need-more-books/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing a book about death. This book will be Jagunbae&amp;rsquo;s first publication.&#xA;I was nervous when I decided to close my restaurant to start a publisher. My heart said I was on the right path, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure if my creation could be a meaningful contribution to the ever-growing space of information.&#xA;My mind played the same question over and over. Does the world need more books? More specifically, does the world need my books?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m writing a book about death. This book will be <a href="https://en.jagunbae.com/">Jagunbae</a>&rsquo;s first publication.</p>
<p>I was nervous when I decided to close my restaurant to start a publisher. My heart said I was on the right path, but I wasn&rsquo;t sure if my creation could be a meaningful contribution to the ever-growing space of information.</p>
<p>My mind played the same question over and over. Does the world need more books? More specifically, does the world need <em>my</em> books?</p>
<p>In South Korea, at least <a href="https://www.eroun.net/news/articleView.html?idxno=34927">60,000 titles were published in 2022</a>. <a href="https://www.mk.co.kr/news/society/10482768">53% of Koreans above 18 don&rsquo;t even read a single book per year</a>. In this country, books in warehouses are stacked like mountains. Clearly, people around me don&rsquo;t read Laozi, Plato, and Adam Smith anymore. Shorts, gossip, and porn have replaced great books.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m not Tom Cruise, and my book is not <em>Mission Impossible</em>. If I want my book to be perused by many, I must convince readers that I crafted attention-worthy content.</p>
<p>I was thrilled to pay for books by Morgan Housel, Tim Ferriss, Derek Sivers, and Rick Rubin because I had gained so much through their previous posts and podcasts. Hearing the news of their upcoming books, I was already sold these creators were committed to helping others and presenting modern classics. Like friends supporting one another, buying these books felt like a private way of saying <em>Thank you</em>.</p>
<p>I want my readers to feel the same. I want to persuade others through consistent work and actions. Sleek copywriting and photography might pull off some sales. But having <em>a New York Times Bestseller</em> badge loses meaning if no one&rsquo;s actually reading it. The grand prize for publishing a book must be the authentic connection through personal ideas and stories. That&rsquo;s why I&rsquo;m determined to share my rocky journey of running a publisher while writing a book.</p>
<p>If an artist comes up to me and says, <em>I&rsquo;m scared because I&rsquo;m not talented enough to compose music like Beethoven or Mozart.</em> I would answer <em>Come on, you haven&rsquo;t even tried yet. Art is not about others. It&rsquo;s about yourself.</em> Why not direct this advice to myself? The world is not waiting for my book. I can&rsquo;t write prose like Ray Bradbury. My book will not be groundbreaking. Still, this book will represent who I really am. Right now, that&rsquo;s enough for me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>These are my favorite blogging platforms and tools</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/blogging/</guid>
      <description>All of these services are subscription-based and privacy-friendly. Let me know if you need help setting up your blog. I&amp;rsquo;d love to help as a fellow blogger.&#xA;Mataroa&#xA;The most affordable blogging platform on the web. Publish for free or pay $9 yearly for custom domain. Great support from the developer. Bear Blog&#xA;Minimal blogging platform. For premium features like custom domain and analytics, pay $5 per month or $48 per year.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>All of these services are subscription-based and privacy-friendly. <a href="https://kangminsuk.com/message/">Let me know</a> if you need help setting up your blog. I&rsquo;d love to help as a fellow blogger.</p>
<p><a href="https://mataroa.blog/">Mataroa</a></p>
<ul>
<li>The most affordable blogging platform on the web. Publish for free or pay $9 yearly for custom domain. Great support from the developer.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://bearblog.dev/">Bear Blog</a></p>
<ul>
<li>Minimal blogging platform. For premium features like custom domain and analytics, pay $5 per month or $48 per year. Possibly the best choice if you&rsquo;re looking for a simple blog with some stylization options.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://micro.blog/">Micro.Blog</a></p>
<ul>
<li>Imagine Mastodon + Blogging. The best choice if you&rsquo;re looking for a communal way of publishing both short and long form content. The platform has an active community of people who&rsquo;ve escaped from big tech social media. Micro.blog offers two premium plans: $5 or $10 per month.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://typora.io/">Typora</a></p>
<ul>
<li>My choice of markdown editor. I like its minimal design, features like focus mode, and customization options like different themes. To me, $15 price tag is reasonable(much cheaper than iA writer). If you&rsquo;re looking for a free option, there&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.marktext.cc/">Marktext</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://wormhole.app/">Wormhole</a></p>
<ul>
<li>Free end-to-end encrypted file sharing tool. Wormhole just works like magic.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Books Only</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/books-only/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/books-only/</guid>
      <description>What if you could spend a day reading books in a quiet space? No need to feel the urge to check Instagram, YouTube, and Email. No need to worry about what to eat and where to go next. Just you and your book. Nothing in between.&#xA;If you want to rest like a reader in the pre-digital era, join us 01-20, 02-03, or 02-17 Saturday from 9 AM to 3 PM at Jagunbae Office(Jeju-si Seosa-ro 173 제주시 서사로 173).</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mataroa.blog/images/5cc981a6.webp" alt="책과나.webp"></p>
<p>What if you could spend a day reading books in a quiet space? No need to feel the urge to check Instagram, YouTube, and Email. No need to worry about what to eat and where to go next. Just you and your book. Nothing in between.</p>
<p>If you want to rest like a reader in the pre-digital era, join us 01-20, 02-03, or 02-17 Saturday from 9 AM to 3 PM at Jagunbae Office(Jeju-si Seosa-ro 173 제주시 서사로 173).</p>
<ul>
<li>The entrance fee for <em>Books Only</em> is 10,000 won. <a href="mailto:kang@jagunbae.com">Email me</a> your name, phone number, and chosen date to join <em>Books Only</em>.</li>
<li>We provide coffee/tea and vegan soup &amp; bread for lunch.</li>
<li>From 9 AM to 3 PM, you can spend as much time as you would like in the office.</li>
<li>Phones, laptops, and other electronic devices are not allowed during <em>Books Only.</em> We ask everyone to put their phones in airplane mode, and they will be stored in a separate box.</li>
<li>You don&rsquo;t have to bring your own books. We have books in both Korean and English.</li>
<li>Quiet and short conversations only. Just like in an old library&rsquo;s study room.</li>
<li>We will be playing ambient music in the background.</li>
</ul>
<p>Again, <a href="mailto:kang@jagunbae.com">email me</a> your name, phone number, and chosen date to join <em>Books Only</em>. See you soon!</p>
<h3 id="reviews">Reviews</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>I can&rsquo;t even remember the last time I focused on reading without checking my phone constantly.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>I finished two books today.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Fresh bread and soup made my day.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Like Books</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/like-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/like-books/</guid>
      <description>*This is a translated version of Ko&amp;rsquo;s original essay in Korean.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve never told anyone that I like books. My reading habit has always been on and off. Even when I was in the mood to read, I switched focus to another book after skimming a few chapters. However, books somehow never left my life. I organized an independent book publishing club in college, got my first job at a publishing company, and now started a publisher myself.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>*<em>This is a translated version of <a href="https://jagunbae.com/love-books/">Ko&rsquo;s original essay in Korean</a>.</em></p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve never told anyone that I like books. My reading habit has always been on and off. Even when I was in the mood to read, I switched focus to another book after skimming a few chapters. However, books somehow never left my life. I organized an independent book publishing club in college, got my first job at a publishing company, and now started a publisher myself. Maybe I need to rethink my feelings toward books. I should be able to tell everyone that I like books.</p>
<p>With a hundred percent chance, books have always taken me somewhere nice. Through books, I&rsquo;ve met incredibly kind people and solved headache-inducing worries. I was sometimes disappointed by the same kind of filler content, but I always sensed the transformative power of words. To me, reading has been the ultimate version of a positive-sum game. Whenever I picked up a book, I was destined to win.</p>
<p>Thanks to the magical medium of books, I had a chance to be friends with the warm-hearted people at &ldquo;Second Read Bookstop.&rdquo;<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> Some say people don&rsquo;t read anymore, but the room was packed with readers from all over Jeju. Some guests returned on the second day to browse more, and many visitors spent more than two hours in the crowded space. Watching the shelves filled with donated books, I realized the books had transported me to somewhere wonderful again.</p>
<p>I enjoyed every second of preparing for Second Read Bookstop, but I was also worried. Would anyone care about a fair about used books? Would people have time for another event at the end of the year? To ease the doubt, I had to constantly remind myself to be immersed in the process, not the result.</p>
<p>Second Read Bookstop made me appreciate more about my lifelong affection for books. Hinge, Larry, and Illy, the three dear friends who organized the event together, share similar feelings. More than ever, we are determined to read, write, and publish more. We all can&rsquo;t wait to find out where books take us next.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Second Read Bookstop, a small festival for book lovers, was held on 23/12/29~30 at Logout Island in Jeju. Ko and her friends organized a second-read books market and showcased exhibits about books and reading.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT is a tool, not my mentor</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/chatgpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/chatgpt/</guid>
      <description>I get it, GPT subscribers. LLMs are getting better at emulating human consciousness. I&amp;rsquo;m also excited about the rapid advancement of AI and how it will shape the future of humanity.&#xA;That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I need to consult with my computer whenever I have a burning question. ChatGPT is a tool, not my mentor. Why would I let AI-generated sentences be the guiding principles of my life?&#xA;Immediate solutions could only be satisfying when asking plain questions such as &amp;ldquo;Where is Korea?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I get it, GPT subscribers. LLMs are getting better at emulating human consciousness. I&rsquo;m also excited about the rapid advancement of AI and how it will shape the future of humanity.</p>
<p>That doesn&rsquo;t mean I need to consult with my computer whenever I have a burning question. ChatGPT is a tool, not my mentor. Why would I let AI-generated sentences be the guiding principles of my life?</p>
<p>Immediate solutions could only be satisfying when asking plain questions such as &ldquo;Where is Korea?&rdquo; There can&rsquo;t be an absolute answer to multifaceted questions like &ldquo;How can I make my business survive a hundred years?&ldquo;AI could provide useful tips, but I must go through years of trial and error myself to learn numerous details of running a sustainable business. Complex tasks like writing a book, running a company, and maintaining relationships deserve a lifetime endeavor.</p>
<p>I refuse to be a docile student of AI-generated wisdom. Some of us are drowning in a never-ending feed of content. Consumers have already lost patience when it comes to entertainment. Should we allow another algorithm to govern our lives?</p>
<p>If you were going to Seoul for the first time, would you entrust ChatGPT as the mastermind behind your itinerary? I don&rsquo;t think so. I&rsquo;m sure you would prefer unique experiences over generic touristy destinations. As a first-time human, that&rsquo;s how I feel about seeking life hacks through feeding prompts into a language model.</p>
<p>I want to get lost and explore the world on my own.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts after reading 1984 by George Orwell</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/1984/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/1984/</guid>
      <description>Who controls the past controls the future: who controls the present controls the past.&#xA;Some thoughts after reading 1984:&#xA;Similar to INGSOC, modern governments seek to control the historical narrative. In South Korea, President Yoon has advocated for downplaying of Japanese colonialism while promoting an &amp;ldquo;anti-communist&amp;rdquo; agenda. Despite confusion among many Koreans about his priorities, Yoon continues to promote his abstract propaganda of &amp;ldquo;free society&amp;rdquo; on the global stage. No one, including Yoon himself, seems to understand the exact meaning of &amp;ldquo;freedom.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Who controls the past controls the future: who controls the present controls the past.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Some thoughts after reading 1984:</p>
<ul>
<li>Similar to INGSOC, modern governments seek to control the historical narrative. In South Korea, President Yoon has advocated for downplaying of Japanese colonialism while promoting an &ldquo;anti-communist&rdquo; agenda. Despite confusion among many Koreans about his priorities, Yoon continues to promote his abstract propaganda of &ldquo;free society&rdquo; on the global stage. No one, including Yoon himself, seems to understand the exact meaning of &ldquo;freedom.&rdquo; On the other hand, his actions suggest that he doesn&rsquo;t value freedom of speech, as he is suing investigative journalists for reporting &ldquo;fake news.&rdquo; Yoon&rsquo;s freedom doesn&rsquo;t mean the equality of opportunity either. In contrast with his pledge to have &ldquo;lots of cabinet members in their 30s,&rdquo; Yoon has filled the government with old political veterans. Unfortunately, just like Yoon, too many elected officials break their initial promises and fixate on political disputes.</li>
<li>I wonder about the realist approach to understanding democracy in our society. In two countries I&rsquo;m most familiar with, the US and South Korea, citizens are always left with two grandpas(rarely a grandma) presidential candidates who are so out-of-touch with the lives of most voters. People become hopeful when an election comes, but the ballot always looks the same. The winner is either a red or blue millionaire. Some questions: is there any viable path to escape from this two-party system? Is election really the best method to choose the leader of a massive community? How can we make politicians to do their jobs? Can &ldquo;Network State&rdquo; be an answer to these perennial problems?</li>
<li>What if most governments are jealous of China&rsquo;s capability to watch its citizens through a sophisticated surveillance model? Some might say democratic nations would not allow China-level unfreedom, but many Koreans and Americans don&rsquo;t mind letting AI intrude into daily lives. Lots of customers are even willing to pay hundreds of dollars to surround themselves with more advanced cameras and speakers. How can we be sure that intelligent agencies can&rsquo;t access the data from tech companies? Naver and Kakao have already handed over hundreds of thousands of personal information to the Korean government. Can we trust Google and Meta to be the trustworthy gatekeepers of privacy? In the end, they are the ones bringing online surveillance to the offline world.</li>
<li>Like Goldstein in 1984, political parties like to create an evil character to incite mass movements. The target could be a former president(two of three former Korean presidents were imprisoned after their time in office) or another nation such as Russia, North Korea, or China. I&rsquo;m not trying to defend these politicians and countries. I want to ensure that I&rsquo;m not merely &ldquo;praying for Ukraine&rdquo; without trying my best to understand the history behind the war. Understanding complicated topics should not be as simple as hitting a &ldquo;like&rdquo; on a YouTube video. I don&rsquo;t want to be the one who&rsquo;s incapable of questioning the existence of Big Brother and Goldstein.</li>
<li>Orwell needed a political purpose to write novels. In his essay <em>Why I Write</em>, Orwell says he writes &ldquo;to make political writing into an art.&rdquo; Then, I wondered what topics would infuriate me the most to start writing. It&rsquo;s a pivotal question. <em>What do I hate the most?</em> I get angry when I see injustice in my community. The rich Korean kids faking SAT scores and deeply-rooted corruption in the Korean army are some examples burning in my heart. Orwell&rsquo;s advice is simple. I must turn this rage into an art.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m writing book reviews</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/review/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be publishing book reviews on this blog.&#xA;My review will be deeply personal. There won&amp;rsquo;t be a 5-star rating or structural analysis. I&amp;rsquo;ll only share what I think is inspirational and interesting about the story. Nothing special, just a man&amp;rsquo;s attempt to have a real conversation with another writer.&#xA;I also hope this series to help me improve my information diet. Perusing books could be the best way to forget about the endless feed of entertainment on social media.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ll be publishing book reviews on this blog.</p>
<p>My review will be deeply personal. There won&rsquo;t be a 5-star rating or structural analysis. I&rsquo;ll only share what I think is inspirational and interesting about the story. Nothing special, just a man&rsquo;s attempt to have a real conversation with another writer.</p>
<p>I also hope this series to help me improve my information diet. Perusing books could be the best way to forget about the endless feed of entertainment on social media.</p>
<p>Let me show you some candidates. It&rsquo;s actually a list of unread books waiting to be opened on my Kindle.</p>
<ul>
<li>1984 by George Orwell.</li>
<li>Animal Farm by George Orwell.</li>
<li>Brave New World by Aldous Huxley.</li>
<li>Fight Club by Chuck Palahniuk.</li>
<li>Fahrenheit 451 by Ray Bradbury.</li>
<li>I, Robot by Isaac Asimov.</li>
<li>Wealth of Nations by Adam Smith.</li>
<li>No Country for Old Men by Ernest Hemingway.</li>
<li>On the Road by Jack Kerouac.</li>
<li>Breakfast of Champions by Kurt Vonnegut.</li>
<li>Catch-22 by Joseph Heller.</li>
<li>The Devil in the White City by Erik Larson.</li>
<li>Snow Crash by Neal Stephenson.</li>
<li>Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas, Hunter S. Thompson.</li>
<li>The Sympathizer by Viet Thanh Nguyen.</li>
<li>John Dies at the End by Jason Pargin.</li>
<li>Slaughterhouse-Five by Kurt Vonnegut.</li>
<li>Crime and Punishment by Fyodor Dostoyevsky.</li>
<li>The Grapes of Wrath by John Steinbeck.</li>
<li>Tomorrow and Tomorrow and Tomorrow by Gabrielle Zevin.</li>
<li>Bear Town by Fredrik Backman.</li>
<li>Cyteen by C.J. Cherryh.</li>
<li>The Night Watchman by Louise Erdrich.</li>
<li>The Sentence by Louise Erdrich.</li>
<li>A Confederacy of Dunces by John Kennedy Tool.</li>
<li>The Fountainhead by Ayn Rand.</li>
<li>The Stranger by Albert Camus.</li>
<li>Beloved by Toni Morrison.</li>
<li>Midnight&rsquo;s Children by Salman Rushdie.</li>
<li>Oblivion by David Foster Wallace.</li>
</ul>
<p>Email me if you have any recommendations. I&rsquo;d also like to read non-fiction books, but finding one without fluff has been difficult. I recently realized reading short essays is much more effective for self-improvement. I could be wrong about this take.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can a restaurant be antifragile?</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/can-a-restaurant-be-antifragile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/can-a-restaurant-be-antifragile/</guid>
      <description>Restaurants are fragile; they compete with each other, but the collective of local restaurants is anti-fragile for that very reason. Nassim Taleb&#xA;Restaurants are concave. Limited upside, larger downside (like short volatility). Mega-fragile to events and circumstances; nonportable and illiquid. Nassim Taleb&#xA;I think that if you want to compete super intensely, you should open a restaurant in DC. There&amp;rsquo;ll be competition — but you won&amp;rsquo;t make any money or do anything.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Restaurants are fragile; they compete with each other, but the collective of local restaurants is anti-fragile for that very reason. <em>Nassim Taleb</em></p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Restaurants are concave. Limited upside, larger downside (like short volatility). Mega-fragile to events and circumstances; nonportable and illiquid. <em>Nassim Taleb</em></p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>I think that if you want to compete super intensely, you should open a restaurant in DC. There&rsquo;ll be competition — but you won&rsquo;t make any money or do anything. <em>Peter Thiel</em></p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>If you offer affordable food with low margins, you can probably pay employees only minimum wage. And you’ll need to squeeze out every efficiency: that’s why restaurants put grandma to work at the register and make kids wash dishes. <em>Peter Thiel</em></p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Starting a great Italian restaurant is not entrepreneurship because the proprietors make no attempt to scale it. Running McDonald’s is not entrepreneurship because they make no serious attempt to build a better product. Apple is an entrepreneurial venture because it is in the business of delivering ever-increasing quality at higher scale. <em>Naval Ravikant</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>According to these well-known business gurus, opening a restaurant is one of the dumbest ideas.</p>
<p>As a restaurant owner, I side with these people. Unpredictable variables often crush reputable restaurants into ashes. Why would you invest your savings into a business destined to cage match with other hundreds? Look around. Only a few restaurants are lucky enough to survive for years. Even the finest restaurants packed with guests struggle to generate enough profit to keep their doors open.</p>
<p>Restaurant management is not getting easier either. We live in an age where the Internet demands all restaurants to be flawless. When everyone can act like a critic, a single bad review is capable of driving a stake into a restaurant&rsquo;s heart. 100 positive reviews can be forgotten very soon, but one bad review always stands out like a diamond.</p>
<p>However, we can set these gloomy facts aside and think differently. What if a restaurant challenges the status quo like a startup? When I decided to start a restaurant without having any experience(yup, I was reckless and deserve to fail miserably), I knew my restaurant had to provide more value than a business of selling food offline. That&rsquo;s why I have treated my sandwich shop as both a restaurant and a media company.</p>
<p>Confused? Here&rsquo;s what my restaurant has done so far:</p>
<ul>
<li>For about two years, the two owners(my wife and I) have sent a weekly newsletter on our own <a href="https://cheesylazy.com/">website</a>. We open-source our recipes and share thoughts about running a small business. We never did ads on any channel, but now we have 127 subscribers from all over the country. Not a million, but it&rsquo;s still notable.</li>
<li>We are working on two projects right now. Our first ebook on starting &ldquo;a too-small-to-fail restaurant&rdquo; and a podcast to interview fellow business owners in Jeju.</li>
<li>A month ago, we began to offer our space for free with future business owners and entrepreneurs. So far, we have accepted three teams and already hosted the first pop-up this week.</li>
</ul>
<p>Of course, the owners put real effort into the food as well. We bake sourdough focaccia, make seven kinds of vegan sauces, and serve fresh veggies all the time. We work at least 12 hours a day to guarantee excellent food and service. It&rsquo;s sometimes difficult to find time/energy to create content, so we push extra on weekends.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m afraid my restaurant will fail if we can&rsquo;t generate meaningful revenue online. Even if we maintain perfect reviews on all platforms, I know there&rsquo;s a clear limit to our success. Most people are unfamiliar with dining at a vegan restaurant. The market is very small, and I can&rsquo;t expect the culture to shift within a few years.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m in an ongoing experiment to substantiate a unique path for restaurants. I don&rsquo;t want to run my restaurant like the Bear; my goal is to create content like the Bear. If we could escape from competition through online media, our restaurant could be the one that lasts a lifetime.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When &#34;critics&#34; visit my restaurant</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/critics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/critics/</guid>
      <description>My 1-year-old sandwich shop has about a hundred reviews all over the Internet. Overall, I&amp;rsquo;m grateful to hear honest feedback because it&amp;rsquo;s my job to check whether my restaurant&amp;rsquo;s providing excellent food and service.&#xA;However, I also meet online &amp;ldquo;critics&amp;rdquo; who tour restaurants to collect reviews on Instagram. When these people enter my restaurant, I can instantly tell they&amp;rsquo;re not interested in any of our products and values. To me, they don&amp;rsquo;t feel like customers.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My <a href="https://reviews.cheesylazy.com/">1-year-old sandwich shop</a> has about a hundred reviews all over the Internet. Overall, I&rsquo;m grateful to hear honest feedback because it&rsquo;s my job to check whether my restaurant&rsquo;s providing excellent food and service.</p>
<p>However, I also meet online &ldquo;critics&rdquo; who tour restaurants to collect reviews on Instagram. When these people enter my restaurant, I can instantly tell they&rsquo;re not interested in any of our products and values. To me, they don&rsquo;t feel like customers.</p>
<p>There&rsquo;s no smile nor &ldquo;hello,&rdquo; these people stride in and take pictures in burst mode. <em>What am I doing here?</em> I murmur while wrapping sandwiches. The food is served, and I hear the iPhone shutter until they&rsquo;re gone. They take a cab to hunt the next review. I clean up the table and leftovers.</p>
<p>In a few days, I encounter their reviews online. But no, I never see them again.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When a loved one&#39;s dying, don&#39;t try to be a doctor</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-06-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-06-09/</guid>
      <description>This is my biggest regret.&#xA;When Mom told me about an 8cm tumor on Dad&amp;rsquo;s spinal cord, I automatically assumed there would be a way out of this nightmare.&#xA;Why be pessimistic this time? Dad had already undergone surgeries and chemo to fend off his cancer. The spinal tumor seemed worse, but some of the best doctors in the country were looking into the case.&#xA;After a week of discussions, the doctors concluded a dissection was the most reasonable solution.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is my biggest regret.</p>
<p>When Mom told me about an 8cm tumor on Dad&rsquo;s spinal cord, I automatically assumed there would be a way out of this nightmare.</p>
<p><em>Why be pessimistic this time?</em> Dad had already undergone surgeries and chemo to fend off his cancer. The spinal tumor seemed worse, but some of the best doctors in the country were looking into the case.</p>
<p>After a week of discussions, the doctors concluded a dissection was the most reasonable solution. I was scared, but I tried my best not to doubt whatever the doctors had to say.</p>
<p>Even after days of googling, I didn&rsquo;t feel entitled to make suggestions for my father&rsquo;s critical condition. Like rooting for Korea in World Cup, I just crossed my fingers and put my trust in the hospital&rsquo;s procedures.</p>
<p>Because I was too focused on the disease, I missed so many chances to have a real conversation with him. I should have asked about his view on death, what he wished to leave behind, and what he wanted to do before the big surgery. Instead, I pushed down my feelings to be rational about the situation.</p>
<p>Looking back, I talked to my father like he was my patient. Even when Dad&rsquo;s condition was clearly getting worse every single day, I prayed for a miracle to stop his pain. I was good at denying reality.</p>
<p>Dad&rsquo;s last days deserved more respect than that of a dying patient. I emptied the urine, massaged his legs, and fed him pills but never asked him how he wanted to spend the last days of his life.</p>
<p>When Dad showed clear signs of dying, I didn&rsquo;t budge to stop a doctor from injecting additional drugs. I was staring at the scene like I was watching a play. I didn&rsquo;t protect Dad&rsquo;s dignity in the last moments.</p>
<p>No human would want to die as a patient. I held his cold hands to finally face my failure to be his son when he needed one.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Random Thoughts #2</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-28/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;re some half-baked thoughts in my notebook.&#xA;I admire people who ask serious questions. What makes humans different from other animals? How did we end up with this political system? How does population density affect urban design? How does media influence the human mind? What is consciousness? What is death? These questions with no correct answers are usually the best ones. Acquiring new skills often starts from learning what and how to observe.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here&rsquo;re some half-baked thoughts in my notebook.</p>
<ul>
<li>I admire people who ask serious questions. What makes humans different from other animals? How did we end up with this political system? How does population density affect urban design? How does media influence the human mind? What is consciousness? What is death? These questions with no correct answers are usually the best ones.</li>
<li>Acquiring new skills often starts from learning what and how to observe. I used to draw like a 6-year-old, but now I can draw like an adult. All thanks to my Drawing 101 course that taught me how to spot and focus on details.</li>
<li>Serious writers are skilled readers.</li>
<li>Master bakers use all five senses to assess the dough.</li>
<li>Listening to a podcast is like reading non-fiction. Listening to music is like reading fiction.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two Days in Seoul</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-23/</guid>
      <description>Maybe humans are not meant to live in a city of 10 million people.&#xA;Last weekend, my wife and I visited Seoul for the first time in about a year. We were excited to see friends and eat great Mexican food(still haven&amp;rsquo;t found a decent Mexican restaurant in Jeju).&#xA;Although we used to live in Seoul for years, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop telling myself, &amp;ldquo;There are so many people and ads.&amp;rdquo; I was like a robot overwhelmed with processing thousands of faces and billboards.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Maybe humans are not meant to live in a city of 10 million people.</p>
<p>Last weekend, my wife and I visited Seoul for the first time in about a year. We were excited to see friends and eat great Mexican food(still haven&rsquo;t found a decent Mexican restaurant in Jeju).</p>
<p>Although we used to live in Seoul for years, I couldn&rsquo;t stop telling myself, &ldquo;<em>There are so many people and ads.</em>&rdquo; I was like a robot overwhelmed with processing thousands of faces and billboards.</p>
<p>Ads, especially the ones in subway stations, were selling <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hagwon">hagwon</a></em> courses, cosmetics, and plastic surgeries. These images were urging all to chase popular jobs and mimic perfect-looking celebrities.</p>
<p>Can you form original ideas after reading hundreds of ad copies every day? Is it even possible to be 100% immune to these messages?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Customers Are Assholes</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-18/</guid>
      <description>Because I run a restaurant, I meet both angels and assholes. Although 99% of our guests are fantastic, a few assholes still find their ways to sneak in and try to ruin the day. I wish I could always ignore them and find peace, but sometimes my feelings get scarred.&#xA;If hospitality means embracing assholes, I must hide my annoyance and provide my best service to everyone entering the restaurant. Even when someone vents frustration on me, I should be poised for the interaction.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Because I run a restaurant, I meet both angels and assholes. Although 99% of our guests are fantastic, a few assholes still find their ways to sneak in and try to ruin the day. I wish I could always ignore them and find peace, but sometimes my feelings get scarred.</p>
<p>If hospitality means embracing assholes, I must hide my annoyance and provide my best service to everyone entering the restaurant. Even when someone vents frustration on me, I should be poised for the interaction.</p>
<p>Understanding assholes takes courage and effort. It&rsquo;s impossible to follow this path without training my brain in mindfulness. To act this way, my body must be drenched with grace and love.</p>
<p>I can also forget about serving assholes and focus on other guests. Maybe someone&rsquo;s got to face these assholes. The assholes would notice they were unwelcome, so most would never consider returning. This could be a wiser choice if I never regret treating some guests differently.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s a dilemma.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A List of My Favorite Tiny Desk Concerts</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-17/</guid>
      <description>NPR&amp;rsquo;s Tiny Desk Concert is one of my favorite content on YouTube. It&amp;rsquo;s nothing like what I hear on other radio stations. I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for Tiny Desk&amp;rsquo;s incredible job at capturing the best out of live music.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve followed Tiny Desk for over 10 years and watched many of the videos. For my own benefit, I organized a list of my personal favorites.&#xA;Suggestions are appreciated. Let me know if there&amp;rsquo;s any artist I&amp;rsquo;m missing.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@nprmusic">NPR</a>&rsquo;s Tiny Desk Concert is one of my favorite content on YouTube. It&rsquo;s nothing like what I hear on other radio stations. I&rsquo;m grateful for Tiny Desk&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e07bI5rz6FY">incredible job</a> at capturing the best out of live music.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve followed Tiny Desk for over 10 years and watched many of the videos. For my own benefit, I organized a list of my personal favorites.</p>
<p><em>Suggestions are appreciated. Let me know if there&rsquo;s any artist I&rsquo;m missing.</em></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N1w-hDiJ4dM">Tyler, The Creator</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QrR_gm6RqCo">Mac Miller</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PBKa-AAy_vo">Daniel Caesar</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hxxcEzM8r-4&amp;pp=ygUJdGlueSBkZXNr">H.E.R.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vkzlU2fDLs8">SIX The Musical</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=McpF_s2wXcY">Juilliard Jazz Ensemble</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4iQmPv_dTI0">Fred again..</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QLRxO9AmNNo">SsingSsing</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=klL7nY1HzaY">Durand Bernarr</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JODaYjDyjyQ">Natalia Lafourcade</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BPRVzA67Dbs">Kenny Beats</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ANPbOxaRIO0">DOMi &amp; JD BECK</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CIjXUg1s5gc">T-Pain</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NwjN3UCBW14">D.R.A.M.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QKzobTCIRDw">Tank And The Bangas</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u3axBzTe2-I">NoSo</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2K49QKVR0p0">Superorganism</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=t8UKQJZsv4o">Weezer</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=USdiumz1ZFM">The Linda Lindas</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A8a2EosJIbM">Hobo Johnson and The Lovemakers</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LTzmjU8aOR4">Saba</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sN58k8tSFXg">Alisa Amador</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tADWPTqR_4A">Julien Baker</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wTqCthvtL8k">Hermanos Gutiérrez</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e4WrRKSgGI0">Lewis Capaldi</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Korean Han and Nunchi</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-15/</guid>
      <description>When Tim Ferriss interviewed Korean American artist Bobby Hundreds, Tim asked a stream of questions to find out why Korean entertainment is taking over the world. Tim was in search of a magic sauce, a concise explanation for the success of Parasite, Squid Game, and BTS.&#xA;To answer Tim&amp;rsquo;s questions, Bobby laid out some Korean words like Han and Nunchi to represent distinct characteristics of Korean culture. Hearing Tim&amp;rsquo;s excitement at these &amp;ldquo;exotic&amp;rdquo; words, I realized Koreanness is being defined by blue-check people outside Korea.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When Tim Ferriss <a href="https://tim.blog/2023/05/11/bobby-hundreds/">interviewed</a> Korean American artist Bobby Hundreds, Tim asked a stream of questions to find out why Korean entertainment is taking over the world. Tim was in search of a magic sauce, a concise explanation for the success of Parasite, Squid Game, and BTS.</p>
<p>To answer Tim&rsquo;s questions, Bobby laid out some Korean words like <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Han_(cultural)">Han</a></em> and <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nunchi">Nunchi</a></em> to represent distinct characteristics of Korean culture. Hearing Tim&rsquo;s excitement at these &ldquo;exotic&rdquo; words, I realized Koreanness is being defined by blue-check people outside Korea.</p>
<p>Trying to blanket the entire population of Korea with these meaningless terms is like claiming all Japanese still carry the samurai spirit. I don&rsquo;t want <em>Han</em> and <em>Nunchi</em> to be the next <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ikigai"><em>Ikigai</em></a> that has become a buzzword in countless self-help books.</p>
<p>Brooding upon the success of Korean entertainment won&rsquo;t provide enlightening life lessons. The rise of Korean soft power is a complicated story that deserves more than &ldquo;there&rsquo;s something different about Koreans.&rdquo;</p>
<p><em>If you&rsquo;re curious about &lsquo;Han,&rsquo; read <a href="https://aeon.co/essays/against-han-or-why-koreans-are-not-defined-by-sadness">this article</a> by Minsoo Kang.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Spoke at a Local University</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-11/</guid>
      <description>Today, my wife and I joined the Content Strategy class at Jeju National University. We were invited to discuss our restaurant&amp;rsquo;s website and content as guest speakers.&#xA;Before I forget, I&amp;rsquo;d like to summarize my presentation to the students.&#xA;The idea to build a vegan sandwich shop was born when we started to ask serious questions about our lives. When working for a company, I wondered if I could be a valuable addition to society.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today, my wife and I joined the Content Strategy class at Jeju National University. We were invited to discuss our restaurant&rsquo;s website and content as guest speakers.</p>
<p>Before I forget, I&rsquo;d like to summarize my presentation to the students.</p>
<ul>
<li>The idea to build a vegan sandwich shop was born when we started to ask serious questions about our lives.</li>
<li>When working for a company, I wondered if I could be a valuable addition to society. I wanted to &ldquo;<a href="https://nav.al/competition-authenticity">escape competition through authenticity</a>,&rdquo; but there were lots of BS around my life. I worked for three companies to realize polishing my resume is not a path to wealth or happiness.</li>
<li>We stopped looking for an ideal setting. Instead, we quit our jobs to create our &ldquo;perfect environment.&rdquo;</li>
<li>We wanted to be the masters of our lives. We didn&rsquo;t want to let competition and jealousy control who we were.</li>
<li>We thought of many business models, but running a vegan sandwich shop was the only one that sparked our imaginations. With this idea, we dreamed of designing and providing a unique product, space, and content.</li>
<li>Before we even knew how to bake sandwich bread, we came up with a set of principles. Five of the principles are 1. Don&rsquo;t let others&rsquo; opinions affect our decisions. 2. Long-term thinking is the way. We focus on small yet constant growth. 3. Hard choices, easy life. No sourcing. We bake bread, make the sauce, and develop our website. 4. Life is short. Mastering one craft is enough. 5. Always creation over consumption.</li>
<li>Our content has similar principles: 1. We publish writings on <a href="https://cheesylazy.com/">our own domain</a>. We don&rsquo;t rely on big-tech platforms to build an audience. 2. We don&rsquo;t let metrics dictate our content. Original content should not be SEO-friendly. 3. Never stop creating and publishing. 4. Help others. We open-source our recipes and know-how. 5. We create content not for a million but for a hundred people.</li>
<li>The cheesylazy.com website I built is simple but effective. Unlike bulky websites and platforms, our website is fast, privacy-friendly, and straightforward.</li>
<li>Our future plans. We&rsquo;re writing a &ldquo;Too Small to Fail&rdquo; e-book and planning to start a podcast interviewing small business owners.</li>
<li>The problems we&rsquo;re considering. 1. Can we be 100% free from Instagram? 2. How can we convince readers to subscribe to our weekly newsletter? 3. How to design a home page. 4. We have over 90 posts now. How can we organize them to be reader-friendly?</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Has Not Changed My World</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-08/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, I listened to Kevin Kelly speaking about AI and its effect on the job market. &amp;ldquo;I still have not seen anyone who lost a job because of AI,&amp;rdquo; he said nonchalantly. His argument stood out because other so-called experts were all screaming about the upcoming AI revolution.&#xA;Sure. ChatGPT passed the bar exam, and Midjourney generated some impressive text-to-image artworks. However, my life has not been impacted at all.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A few days ago, I listened to Kevin Kelly speaking about AI and its effect on the job market. &ldquo;I still have not seen anyone who lost a job because of AI,&rdquo; he said nonchalantly. His argument stood out because other so-called experts were all screaming about the upcoming AI revolution.</p>
<p>Sure. ChatGPT passed the bar exam, and Midjourney generated some impressive text-to-image artworks. However, my life has not been impacted at all. I still bake bread, clean floors, wash dishes, and write articles. AI&rsquo;s not part of my life yet.</p>
<p>Humans are attracted to doomsday prophecies. When will the volcano erupt? When will the nuclear war begin? When will we achieve AGI? These questions are worth asking only if someone&rsquo;s trying to prevent a potential catastrophe. Otherwise, &ldquo;The world is ending anyway&rdquo; mentality is the fertile ground for helplessness and meaninglessness.</p>
<p>Talking about AI is entertaining. That&rsquo;s why the content around AI is sweeping the Internet. Nonetheless, I don&rsquo;t have to squeeze AI into my life. I just want to execute my job well.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Korean NPCs</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-07/</guid>
      <description>As a Korean struggling to escape from NPCness, let me tell you how a Korean NPC thinks.&#xA;Happiness lies in getting into med school and becoming a doctor. There is no &amp;ldquo;Korean Steve Jobs&amp;rdquo; because our education system obliterates creativity. If you become a government worker, your life is set because you&amp;rsquo;re guaranteed a pension. Never trust Korean media. New York Times and CNN are the most trustworthy media in the world.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a Korean struggling to escape from NPCness, let me tell you how a Korean NPC thinks.</p>
<ul>
<li>Happiness lies in getting into med school and becoming a doctor.</li>
<li>There is no &ldquo;Korean Steve Jobs&rdquo; because our education system obliterates creativity.</li>
<li>If you become a government worker, your life is set because you&rsquo;re guaranteed a pension.</li>
<li>Never trust Korean media. New York Times and CNN are the most trustworthy media in the world.</li>
<li>Waiting in line for hours to enter a trendy restaurant is solely for my pleasure(It&rsquo;s not for Instagram).</li>
<li>Moving to Australia, Canada, or the US will solve my problems in Korea.</li>
<li>K-pop has nothing to do with online propaganda.</li>
<li>To get married, you need a stable job and apartment.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Random Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-06/</guid>
      <description>In Korea, poor kids study English while rich kids study in English. I&amp;rsquo;ll never let a tiny scratch on my car ruin the day. I read fiction to remind myself I&amp;rsquo;m merely a speck in the vast universe. Great bakers respect time, temperature, and hydration. Humor could be the best indicator to gauge someone&amp;rsquo;s intelligence and creativity. It was Children&amp;rsquo;s Day in Korea yesterday. I had a moment of silence for all the children who would not be born because of the country&amp;rsquo;s lowest fertility rate in the world.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In Korea, poor kids study English while rich kids study in English.</li>
<li>I&rsquo;ll never let a tiny scratch on my car ruin the day.</li>
<li>I read fiction to remind myself I&rsquo;m merely a speck in the vast universe.</li>
<li>Great bakers respect time, temperature, and hydration.</li>
<li>Humor could be the best indicator to gauge someone&rsquo;s intelligence and creativity.</li>
<li>It was Children&rsquo;s Day in Korea yesterday. I had a moment of silence for all the children who would not be born because of the country&rsquo;s lowest fertility rate in the world.</li>
<li>Praying doesn&rsquo;t solve problems. Actions do.</li>
<li>&ldquo;I want to&rdquo; is a trap. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m doing&rdquo; is much better.</li>
<li>Plastic straws are gone. Private jets are flying.</li>
<li>Politicians scream, &ldquo;Why can&rsquo;t we create Korean ChatGPT?&rdquo; Not a single of them has written code before.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Internship</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-05/</guid>
      <description>After getting my college degree in the US, I returned to Korea to enlist in the military.&#xA;When I was discharged from a 21-month service in the army, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what I wanted to do next. I considered preparing for LEET(Legal Education Eligibility Test) to join a law school but soon realized I had no interest in becoming a lawyer.&#xA;I wished for an opportunity to escape from the trench of boredom and anxiety.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After getting my college degree in the US, I returned to Korea to enlist in the military.</p>
<p>When I was discharged from a 21-month service in the army, I didn&rsquo;t know what I wanted to do next. I considered preparing for LEET(Legal Education Eligibility Test) to join a law school but soon realized I had no interest in becoming a lawyer.</p>
<p>I wished for an opportunity to escape from the trench of boredom and anxiety. Using a stack of LEET prep books as a pillow, I found myself checking job postings every day. Without telling anyone, I wrote a sloppy resume and CV and sent them to a bunch of companies. A few days later, I received an offer to intern at a travel startup in Seoul.</p>
<p>The internship was incredible. The business development team I joined had the most passionate people in the company. The service was growing fast, and I could freely suggest and lead any projects. I didn&rsquo;t mind putting in extra hours because I could see I was making a difference.</p>
<p>A few weeks before my 3-month contract ended, my team leader offered me to stay in the company to work as a full-time manager. This meeting surprised me because I never thought of becoming a business manager. I wasn&rsquo;t sure if I wanted to be committed to this career path. My brain was jumbled with futile questions like &ldquo;What am I good at?&rdquo; and &ldquo;What&rsquo;s my passion?&rdquo;</p>
<p>I eventually made up my mind and messaged her to say I was interested. I still had to be interviewed by the company&rsquo;s CEO and COO before signing a new contract. Because my contract was ending soon, HR set up the interview on the last day of my internship.</p>
<p>I wasn&rsquo;t prepared to prove my value to the company. I didn&rsquo;t even know what I wanted to do with my life. I noticed the interviewers didn&rsquo;t have enough time to read my resume either. They asked whether I was genuinely interested in being part of the startup&rsquo;s mission. In return, I gave them half-baked answers I had overheard in a podcast.</p>
<p>I tried my best to sound smart, but everyone in the room knew I was the exact opposite.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More About Our Restaurant CHEESYLAZY</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/cheesylazy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/cheesylazy/</guid>
      <description>Since May 2022, my wife and I have been running CHEESYLAZY, a vegan sandwich shop in Jeju, South Korea.&#xA;What&amp;rsquo;s so special? We write a weekly newsletter on our website. We share recipes we developed and publish essays about our experience and philosophy. We&amp;rsquo;ve written over 80 posts and currently have about a hundred subscribers. We have fantastic reviews on all sites such as Happy Cow, Google, Naver, and Kakao. Our food is fresh and original.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since May 2022, my wife and I have been running CHEESYLAZY, a vegan sandwich shop in Jeju, South Korea.</p>
<h3 id="whats-so-special">What&rsquo;s so special?</h3>
<ul>
<li>We write a weekly newsletter on our <a href="https://jagunbae.com/">website</a>. We share recipes we developed and publish essays about our experience and philosophy. We&rsquo;ve written over 80 posts and currently have about a hundred subscribers.</li>
<li>We have <a href="https://reviews.cheesylazy.com">fantastic reviews on all sites</a> such as Happy Cow, Google, Naver, and Kakao.</li>
<li>Our food is fresh and original. We bake our bread twice a day and make almost all the ingredients ourselves. For example, pickles, kombucha, mayonnaise, hot sauce, romesco sauce, tofu cheese, smoked cheese, parsley pesto, teriyaki sauce, and chili are all housemade.</li>
<li>We aspire to be more than a restaurant. We&rsquo;re writing our first e-book titled &ldquo;Too Small to Fail - How to Start a Small Restaurant.&rdquo; We&rsquo;re also planning on hosting a podcast to interview independent business owners in Jeju.</li>
<li>We also update our <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLEnNOs6dh8HmuTkrP5Hd0rUmdjOXXVdsS">200 songs playlist</a> on a daily basis.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Thoughts on Marriage</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-03/</guid>
      <description>My wife and I run a restaurant together, hang out with friends together, and write a newsletter together. Our relationship is the most remarkable quality of my life. We literally spend 24/7 with each other and rarely have a serious argument.&#xA;Some thoughts about our relationship&amp;hellip;&#xA;We don&amp;rsquo;t hide anything. I don&amp;rsquo;t hold in farts in front of my wife. I just let them out like I&amp;rsquo;m alone. Freedom of speech is guaranteed as well.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My wife and I run a restaurant together, hang out with friends together, and write a newsletter together. Our relationship is the most remarkable quality of my life. We literally spend 24/7 with each other and rarely have a serious argument.</p>
<p>Some thoughts about our relationship&hellip;</p>
<ul>
<li>We don&rsquo;t hide anything. I don&rsquo;t hold in farts in front of my wife. I just let them out like I&rsquo;m alone. Freedom of speech is guaranteed as well. We say whatever we think it&rsquo;s funny.</li>
<li>I often feel like she knows more about me than I know myself. Sometimes, we don&rsquo;t even have to say anything to communicate. I just know when she wants to grab an ice cream.</li>
<li>We have small fights to prevent big arguments. It&rsquo;s like using small fires to prevent large wildfires. Whenever I get hurt by what she says, I try to express my emotions immediately. Buddhist mentality is the way. I try my best to avoid suppressing feelings before I get consumed by anger.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Literature Major</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-02/</guid>
      <description>In college, I majored in Asian Literature. For three and a half years, I spent many hours reading books from Palestine, Egypt, Japan, Taiwan. and Mainland China.&#xA;I still don&amp;rsquo;t know what attracted me to Literature. Although I dabbled in Geology, Physics, Psychology, Journalism, and Philosophy courses, I found reading fiction and analyzing it most fascinating.&#xA;I was a lucky kid who had unconditional support from my parents. I didn&amp;rsquo;t worry about securing a job after graduation and didn&amp;rsquo;t even consider applying to grad school to become a Literature professor.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In college, I majored in Asian Literature. For three and a half years, I spent many hours reading books from Palestine, Egypt, Japan, Taiwan. and Mainland China.</p>
<p>I still don&rsquo;t know what attracted me to Literature. Although I dabbled in Geology, Physics, Psychology, Journalism, and Philosophy courses, I found reading fiction and analyzing it most fascinating.</p>
<p>I was a lucky kid who had unconditional support from my parents. I didn&rsquo;t worry about securing a job after graduation and didn&rsquo;t even consider applying to grad school to become a Literature professor. I dismissed people warning me I was &ldquo;paying a lot of money to be a Starbucks barista.&rdquo; When choosing courses, my main goal was to have fun as much as possible. That&rsquo;s why I never skipped a class.</p>
<p>What did I learn from studying Literature? Nothing special really. Attending college is unnecessary if you intend to read books and learn how to write. However, I have no regrets about immersing myself in the works of Soseki and Lu Xun. I&rsquo;m grateful for the professors who returned my essays loaded with pages of feedback. There&rsquo;s no way to find out if my expensive education was actually worth it. I can only say I wouldn&rsquo;t be the same person without the years I spent studying novels. I&rsquo;m happy with this answer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Desire to Be Associated With Celebrities</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-05-01/</guid>
      <description>Eight years ago, I saw Leonardo DiCaprio at an Italian restaurant in NYC. I was with my sister, and he was sitting right across from our table. He used a back door to enter the restaurant, so my sister and I were the only guests who knew the most famous actor in the world was eating pasta in the same space.&#xA;When he was leaving the restaurant, I stood up and asked him to take pictures with me.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Eight years ago, I saw Leonardo DiCaprio at an Italian restaurant in NYC. I was with my sister, and he was sitting right across from our table. He used a back door to enter the restaurant, so my sister and I were the only guests who knew the most famous actor in the world was eating pasta in the same space.</p>
<p>When he was leaving the restaurant, I stood up and asked him to take pictures with me. My voice was shaky, but he somehow understood what I wanted. We took about a minute to snap pictures then he left saying goodbye. Soon after he was gone, people flocked to our table asking &ldquo;Was that Leo?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Yes, I posted the pictures on Facebook and checked the comments and likes every five minutes. Since then, I must have told this story to dozens of friends. Although I often said &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t care about celebrities,&rdquo; a desire to be associated with them was always inside me.</p>
<p>The longing to be associated with famous people seems like human nature. I always see people posting pictures with celebrities, visiting cafes owned by celebrities, and buying books by celebrities.</p>
<p>Arguably, the number of followers has become the most prevalent measurement of clout. Maybe it&rsquo;s becoming even harder to be totally indifferent to celebrities.</p>
<p><em>It was a difficult choice. I decided not to attach my photo with DiCaprio.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should Conversations be Productized?</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-30/</guid>
      <description>My wife and I had great conversations with our friends today. Like us, they&amp;rsquo;re small business owners who want their work to reflect who they are. Whenever we meet, we never run out of stories to share.&#xA;After hearing about their concerns, projects, and plans, I was instantly motivated to jumpstart my ongoing tasks. My friends&amp;rsquo; perspectives on maintaining and transforming business felt so valuable that I wished I could record the conversation.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My wife and I had great conversations with our friends today. Like us, they&rsquo;re small business owners who want their work to reflect who they are. Whenever we meet, we never run out of stories to share.</p>
<p>After hearing about their concerns, projects, and plans, I was instantly motivated to jumpstart my ongoing tasks. My friends&rsquo; perspectives on maintaining and transforming business felt so valuable that I wished I could record the conversation.</p>
<p>When amazing conversations end, I get sad because I know I&rsquo;ll forget the details in a few days. It&rsquo;s a bummer that I rely on my faulty memories to rewind what I&rsquo;ve learned from the discussions. I wonder if recording conversations with other business owners and putting them out to the world would be a good idea.</p>
<p>What do you think? Does &ldquo;<a href="https://nav.al/productize-yourself">productize yourself</a>&rdquo; mean I should productize my interactions with friends? I&rsquo;m sure many more would benefit from listening to the talk between passionate business owners. At the same time, I could also miss opportunities to form authentic relationships. If I&rsquo;m speaking to a mic while staring at a friend, can I really say I&rsquo;m not being pretentious?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Business Is a Filter</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-29/</guid>
      <description>I like to think of my restaurant as a filter, not a magnet. My restaurant serves vegan food, doesn&amp;rsquo;t do any ads, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t even have a sign outside. Not because I despise money but because I want to serve a small community of people who understand my values.&#xA;The marketing strategy for the restaurant is very simple. My wife and I write a weekly newsletter on our website. We share lessons from opening and operating a restaurant, vegan recipes we&amp;rsquo;re using for the menu, and our thoughts on values such as success and freedom.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I like to think of my restaurant as a filter, not a magnet. My restaurant serves vegan food, doesn&rsquo;t do any ads, and doesn&rsquo;t even have a sign outside. Not because I despise money but because I want to serve a small community of people who understand my values.</p>
<p>The marketing strategy for the restaurant is very simple. My wife and I write a weekly newsletter on our <a href="https://cheesylazy.com/">website</a>. We share lessons from opening and operating a restaurant, vegan recipes we&rsquo;re using for the menu, and our thoughts on values such as success and freedom. We&rsquo;ve been publishing for over a year and now have a hundred subscribers.</p>
<p>How do we make a living? Because the rent is cheap, we don&rsquo;t have to attract a hundred guests daily to make it even. Because the fixed costs are low, we get to focus more on delivering better food, service, and content. My goal is to protect this virtuous cycle.</p>
<p>Fortunately, we have a steady flow of customers. Many of whom found us through our online writing. I can&rsquo;t estimate what percentage of the customers know about our website, but I appreciate some recognize us as more than just a sandwich shop.</p>
<p>So, what&rsquo;s the next step? I certainly don&rsquo;t want to run a popular restaurant with long wait times. That&rsquo;s why I never plan to launch a big promotional campaign. Instead, I want to create a podcast that celebrates one-of-a-kind creators and business owners. Will this work? I don&rsquo;t know. Would I be a fan of this kind of content? For sure.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Best Haircut</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-28/</guid>
      <description>My wife and I got haircuts today. We had been discussing the desperate need for haircuts for over a month, so we decided to walk into a salon closest to our restaurant.&#xA;The place had zero online reviews and had no customers inside. However, since we never liked to waste time and money on beauty maintenance, we decided to go in and take a chance.&#xA;To our surprise, the salon turned out to be the best we&amp;rsquo;ve found in the city.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My wife and I got haircuts today. We had been discussing the desperate need for haircuts for over a month, so we decided to walk into a salon closest to our restaurant.</p>
<p>The place had zero online reviews and had no customers inside. However, since we never liked to waste time and money on beauty maintenance, we decided to go in and take a chance.</p>
<p>To our surprise, the salon turned out to be the best we&rsquo;ve found in the city. Here are a few reasons:</p>
<ul>
<li>The stylist was very attentive and washed our hair twice, both before and after the haircuts. In addition, she spent at least 30 minutes on each of us. We were grateful for this level of service. Affordable places don&rsquo;t usually do this.</li>
<li>She never asked us any personal questions. I&rsquo;ve been to some cheap barber shops, and all the barbers always lectured me about &ldquo;how to run a successful business.&rdquo; As someone who simply wanted a haircut, I was relieved to not have to deal with unnecessary conversations.</li>
<li>The prices were extremely reasonable, with men&rsquo;s haircuts at 12,000 won and women&rsquo;s at 14,000 won. The cheapest haircut I had was 10,000 won, but it had much worse service. 12,000 won for an excellent haircut is such a bargain.</li>
</ul>
<p>After getting the best haircut of the year, my wife and I talked about how we relied on online reviews to assess the quality of a business. Reviews are often helpful, but could also be a barrier between me and hidden gems.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m so used to searching for others&rsquo; approvals before trying them on my own. Before watching a show on Netflix, I go on Metacritic and Rotten Tomatoes. Before walking into a coffee shop, I check reviews on Naver and Kakao. Whenever it&rsquo;s time to try something new, I still act like a child so scared of being responsible for my choices.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Butt Does All the Hard Work</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Listen, butt does all the hard work.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Dad used to say this whenever we went to a sauna together. He had this theory that most people forget to take care of their butt even though it&amp;rsquo;s the one doing all the &amp;ldquo;dirty jobs&amp;rdquo; for us.&#xA;Dad&amp;rsquo;s favorite spot in the sauna was a warm pool equipped with really strong massage jets. When we entered that pool, he immediately pushed massage buttons for both of us.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Listen, butt does all the hard work.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Dad used to say this whenever we went to a sauna together. He had this theory that most people forget to take care of their butt even though it&rsquo;s the one doing all the &ldquo;dirty jobs&rdquo; for us.</p>
<p>Dad&rsquo;s favorite spot in the sauna was a warm pool equipped with really strong massage jets. When we entered that pool, he immediately pushed massage buttons for both of us. &ldquo;Make sure to massage your butt,&rdquo; he never forgot to remind me.</p>
<p>We were the two boys moving butts in a circle to make sure the jets were touching the entire muscles. We were quiet and focused. And this ritual lasted for at least five minutes.</p>
<p>I still go to a sauna sometimes and think about these memories with Dad. We had some of the most honest conversations while we were literally naked. He also scrubbed my back, massaged my ears, and boosted my confidence saying I was good-looking. I never knew I would look back on those moments, but here I am. I miss my sauna buddy today.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Korean Identity</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-26/</guid>
      <description>When I moved to the US, kids at my high school called me Jackie Chan, Ichiro, and Yao Ming. I always wanted to tell them, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m Korean, not Chinese nor Japanese&amp;rdquo; but couldn&amp;rsquo;t really speak English at that time.&#xA;Maybe alienation forces people to think deeply about their individuality. Before I met people who were oblivious to Korean culture, I never imagined my Koreanness could be made fun of by someone else.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I moved to the US, kids at my high school called me Jackie Chan, Ichiro, and Yao Ming. I always wanted to tell them, &ldquo;I&rsquo;m Korean, not Chinese nor Japanese&rdquo; but couldn&rsquo;t really speak English at that time.</p>
<p>Maybe alienation forces people to think deeply about their individuality. Before I met people who were oblivious to Korean culture, I never imagined my Koreanness could be made fun of by someone else. The moment I realized my identity would stand out, I began asking many questions about my identity.</p>
<p>In Korea, most discussions about Korean identity revolve around nationalism and pessimism. That&rsquo;s why I find the works of Korean American artists like Lee Isaac Chung and Min Jin Lee refreshing.</p>
<p>Minari and Pachinko feel authentic because they are inspired by the writers&rsquo; understanding of their Korean identity. These stories are not about projecting perfect images of Korea. There&rsquo;s no political agenda. They grew up feeling different from others, and this experience became the creative engine for their crafts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bear Blog and a Notepad</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s the best note-taking software?&amp;rdquo; used to be my favorite question.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve tried a number of productivity apps. I subscribed to services like Readwise, Notion, Roam, Logseq, and Obsidian. I also searched for a better search engine than Google. So I&amp;rsquo;ve switched my default search to Kagi, You, Neeva, and DuckDuckGo. Before discovering Bear Blog, I wrote on WordPress, Ghost, Substack, and Write.as.&#xA;I cared so much about finding the best tools for my productivity.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;What&rsquo;s the best note-taking software?&rdquo; used to be my favorite question.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve tried a number of productivity apps. I subscribed to services like Readwise, Notion, Roam, Logseq, and Obsidian. I also searched for a better search engine than Google. So I&rsquo;ve switched my default search to Kagi, You, Neeva, and DuckDuckGo. Before discovering Bear Blog, I wrote on WordPress, Ghost, Substack, and Write.as.</p>
<p>I cared so much about finding the best tools for my productivity. I spent too much time looking for a shortcut. When I felt stuck, I automatically handed my problems over to new trending software.</p>
<p>I canceled most subscriptions, but I&rsquo;m more productive than ever. I stopped using read-it-later apps like Readwise Reader, Matter, and Instapaper as well. Now I read on Kindle, jot down random thoughts on a small notepad, and move these words to Bear Blog.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t need to think about PKM anymore. To write and publish, I only need to make sure I&rsquo;m carrying a notepad.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Busy, and It&#39;s Great</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-23/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really busy these days. I have to run a restaurant with my wife, publish a daily post here, and paint walls in a house we&amp;rsquo;ll soon be moving into.&#xA;Our restaurant is closed on Sundays and Mondays, but I still have to spend the bulk of Mondays prepping ingredients. My wife and I have Sundays to take a break from work, but we&amp;rsquo;ve decided to self-paint our new house. Ta-da.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m really busy these days. I have to run a restaurant with my wife, publish a daily post here, and paint walls in a house we&rsquo;ll soon be moving into.</p>
<p>Our restaurant is closed on Sundays and Mondays, but I still have to spend the bulk of Mondays prepping ingredients. My wife and I have Sundays to take a break from work, but we&rsquo;ve decided to self-paint our new house. Ta-da. Sundays are now reserved for applying putty and sanding walls.</p>
<p>There&rsquo;s no time to waste. When I became obsessed with my daily routine, my time suddenly became way more precious.</p>
<p>Two years ago, when I quit my job as a marketing manager, I felt like I was drowning in too much free time. I could sleep as much as I wanted and learn whatever I enjoyed. However, I struggled to focus on a single task.</p>
<p>Although I had numerous ideas, like writing a blog and learning to bake, I couldn&rsquo;t sustain a habit of working on them. I was constantly distracted because I had too many options. I wasted so many hours because nothing forced me to be busy.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s wonderful to be busy. I&rsquo;m terrible at keeping track of to-do lists, but I&rsquo;m capable of following a simple schedule filled with meaningful work.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Don&#39;t Care About Politics</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-22/</guid>
      <description>When I was ten-year-old, I read three different newspapers. My favorite section was politics. Likely because my mom was a politician who wrote columns in local newspapers.&#xA;I thought memorizing the names of famous politicians was necessary to be a smart person. Although I could never figure out why the two parties had to disagree on every topic, I was still proud that I could tell who was on which side.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I was ten-year-old, I read three different newspapers. My favorite section was politics. Likely because my mom was a politician who wrote columns in local newspapers.</p>
<p>I thought memorizing the names of famous politicians was necessary to be a smart person. Although I could never figure out why the two parties had to disagree on every topic, I was still proud that I could tell who was on which side.</p>
<p>Even in college, I cared so much about Korean politics. When Park Geun-hye&rsquo;s corruption scandal rattled the entire country, I was so furious that I ran to a stationary store to buy a paper board and colored papers to concoct a &ldquo;Park Must Resign&rdquo; protest sign.</p>
<p>I was studying in the US but still held the sign in front of the university&rsquo;s main library. No one, besides Koreans, even knew who Park was. I still felt like I was participating in a historical movement.</p>
<p>8 years have passed, and I don&rsquo;t care about politics anymore. Being obsessed with the news for 15 years only caused anxiety and helplessness. Instead of feeling angry about another political scandal, I now try my best to look for timeless wisdom in books.</p>
<p>Watching a bunch of politicians quarreling with each other is never worth my time. My goal is to disconnect myself from politics for a long time until I forget who&rsquo;s on which side.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Wear My Dad&#39;s Clothes</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-21/</guid>
      <description>When Dad passed away, he left behind a lot of clothes. Most of them are really nice clothes from his favorite brand Bogner.&#xA;I wanted to keep them as much as possible. With Mom&amp;rsquo;s help, I tried on all the clothes and brought many of them to my house.&#xA;His pants are a little too short, so I pretend they&amp;rsquo;re ankle-length pants. Some sleeves are short, but I wear them as 3/4 sleeve jackets.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When Dad passed away, he left behind a lot of clothes. Most of them are really nice clothes from his favorite brand Bogner.</p>
<p>I wanted to keep them as much as possible. With Mom&rsquo;s help, I tried on all the clothes and brought many of them to my house.</p>
<p>His pants are a little too short, so I pretend they&rsquo;re ankle-length pants. Some sleeves are short, but I wear them as 3/4 sleeve jackets. The size is not perfect, but I still love how comfy they are. Dad certainly had great taste in clothing. In terms of fashion, he and I value nothing but practicality.</p>
<p>Inheriting Dad&rsquo;s collection has pushed me to believe in the importance of minimalism. I no longer think of buying more clothes. Seeing the aftermath of Dad&rsquo;s passing, I realized I don&rsquo;t want my future self to feel sorry about the stuff I&rsquo;ve accumulated.</p>
<p>Wearing Dad&rsquo;s clothes became my first step towards a simpler life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Thoughts About Korea</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-20/</guid>
      <description>At my restaurant, I often get a chance to chat with non-Korean customers living or planning to live in S. Korea. I always find their optimistic perspectives on Korea refreshing because I tend to focus too much on the negative aspects of my country.&#xA;On the news, Korea is famous for its world&amp;rsquo;s lowest fertility rate, exceptionally high suicide rate, and chaebol-controlled economy. According to these statistics, Korea doesn&amp;rsquo;t even look like an okay place to live.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At my restaurant, I often get a chance to chat with non-Korean customers living or planning to live in S. Korea. I always find their optimistic perspectives on Korea refreshing because I tend to focus too much on the negative aspects of my country.</p>
<p>On the news, Korea is famous for its <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2022/08/26/asia/south-korea-worlds-lowest-fertility-rate-intl-hnk/index.html">world&rsquo;s lowest fertility rate</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suicide_in_South_Korea">exceptionally high suicide rate</a>, and <a href="https://etonomics.com/2022/06/07/chaebols-of-south-korea/">chaebol-controlled economy</a>. According to these statistics, Korea doesn&rsquo;t even look like an okay place to live.</p>
<p>So, what makes Korea appealing? I can come up with a couple answers.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>It&rsquo;s remarkably safe to live in Korea. I can walk around alone at 2AM without worrying about my safety. Surveillance cameras are everywhere, and no one dares to steal others&rsquo; stuff. In a coffee shop, people leave their laptops on a table when they go to the bathroom. It&rsquo;s rare to find homeless people and extremely difficult to even see a gun. Even if someone pulls out a gun in a crowded street, Koreans will walk past thinking it&rsquo;s just a toy. 119(ambulance) and 112(police) emergency services are reliable as well.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Koreans are friendly towards English-speaking foreigners. Almost all Koreans have spent numerous years studying English. If English is your native language, many Koreans will look up to you simply because you speak the language they&rsquo;ve tried so hard to master. As an English speaker, you don&rsquo;t have to learn Korean to live here. Ironically, Koreans will blame themselves for not understanding your English.</p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing My Two Cats</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-19/</guid>
      <description>My wife and I are living with two amazing cats. Zong-ka, in the first picture, is 10 years old. Ban-ban, in the second, is about 10 months old.&#xA;Watching Zong-ka and Ban-ban eating, playing, and sleeping is one of the greatest joys.&#xA;I had never raised a cat until I met my wife. When I first met Zong-ka in my wife&amp;rsquo;s tiny studio, Zong-ka was so scared of me that he ran straight into the bathroom.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My wife and I are living with two amazing cats. Zong-ka, in the first picture, is 10 years old. Ban-ban, in the second, is about 10 months old.</p>
<p>Watching Zong-ka and Ban-ban eating, playing, and sleeping is one of the greatest joys.</p>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1681915630-0.webp" alt="Kang"></p>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1681915645-0.webp" alt="Kang"></p>
<p>I had never raised a cat until I met my wife. When I first met Zong-ka in my wife&rsquo;s tiny studio, Zong-ka was so scared of me that he ran straight into the bathroom. I remember feeling terrible because I knew Zong-ka hated touching the water. Three years later, I wish I could say he loves me, but at least he doesn&rsquo;t hate me anymore. We&rsquo;re good friends.</p>
<p>7 months ago, I spotted Ban-ban crawling through a six-lane road near my house. I was waiting for a green light. As soon as I could go across, I ran to check on the cat, hiding under a bush on the edge of the road. She seemed unharmed. I slowly approached to hold her with two hands. I didn&rsquo;t have much time to think, but I was sure she would run away. However, she didn&rsquo;t even flinch. I hugged her tightly in my arms and walked fast to my house. That&rsquo;s how Ban-ban became a new member of our house.</p>
<p>All four of us fall asleep on the same bed. In the morning, we humans wake up to the sound of our cats. At night, the cats always wait by the door when we humans return home after long hours working at the restaurant. I never get tired of living with these two cats.</p>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1681915660-0.webp" alt="Kang"></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revising my old writings</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-18/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been publishing a post every day for more than two weeks. Writing daily has been really fun, and I intend to continue this habit for at least a year(maybe until the day I die. Who knows?).&#xA;Every morning, when I wake up, I grab my phone immediately and reread the post I published the night before. With half-closed eyes, I fix a few words and then start brushing my teeth.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been publishing a post every day for more than two weeks. Writing daily has been really fun, and I intend to continue this habit for at least a year(maybe until the day I die. Who knows?).</p>
<p>Every morning, when I wake up, I grab my phone immediately and reread the post I published the night before. With half-closed eyes, I fix a few words and then start brushing my teeth.</p>
<p>I enjoy the seemingly endless process of revising. Some might argue spending energy on the next post is wiser, but I can&rsquo;t let go of my past writings. Even if no one&rsquo;s reading, I revisit my old posts and start working on them.</p>
<p>More views are great, but better writings are more important. To me, revising is like cleaning a house. It&rsquo;s the least I can do to welcome my guests.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watch Out for Envy</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Watch out for envy.&amp;rdquo; My dad used to say too many people waste their lives feeling jealous of others.&#xA;Koreans are raised to be test-takers. Teenagers battle for a better score on a college entrance exam. College graduates devote themselves to all kinds of eligibility tests. In this land, too many people spend years beating others on competitive exams to be accountants, government workers, public school teachers, real estate agents, and journalists.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Watch out for envy.&rdquo; My dad used to say too many people waste their lives feeling jealous of others.</p>
<p>Koreans are raised to be test-takers. Teenagers battle for a better score on a college entrance exam. College graduates devote themselves to all kinds of eligibility tests. In this land, too many people spend years beating others on competitive exams to be accountants, government workers, public school teachers, real estate agents, and journalists.</p>
<p>Steeped in zero-sum games, it&rsquo;s difficult to realize there&rsquo;s a way out of the competition. When tests are the ultimate purpose of life, getting into a med school or law school becomes the highest form of achievement. To test-takers, success forever means winning over others.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m not a test-taker. I don&rsquo;t want to be trapped in binary thinking. The world is much more than a community of winners and losers. There&rsquo;s no need to be jealous of other restaurant owners&rsquo; and writers&rsquo; accomplishments. Their success doesn&rsquo;t affect my craft. I only need to carry on with a &ldquo;win and help others win&rdquo; mindset.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WeVPN Is Gone</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-16/</guid>
      <description>WeVPN just shut down its service. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the service for about a year, and I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to get any refund for the rest of my 2-year subscription. Fortunately, the monthly subscription fee was less than $3, so I&amp;rsquo;m not too shocked about the news.&#xA;A year ago, when looking for a paid VPN service, I searched &amp;ldquo;the best VPN&amp;rdquo; and read some recommendation articles(aka paid promotions). I didn&amp;rsquo;t spend enough time researching the best quality and reliability.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>WeVPN just shut down its service. I&rsquo;ve been using the service for about a year, and I won&rsquo;t be able to get any refund for the rest of my 2-year subscription. Fortunately, the monthly subscription fee was less than $3, so I&rsquo;m not too shocked about the news.</p>
<p>A year ago, when looking for a paid VPN service, I searched &ldquo;the best VPN&rdquo; and read some recommendation articles(aka paid promotions). I didn&rsquo;t spend enough time researching the best quality and reliability. I only cared about comparing the prices of different services. I assumed all VPN companies provided similar features and never thought software could shut down without giving any clear explanations.</p>
<p>Clearly, I made a dumb mistake. I hope not, but I can&rsquo;t even be sure if WeVPN did anything malicious with the users&rsquo; data.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve realized that I need to pay more attention to the longevity of the apps and software I subscribe to. It&rsquo;s essential to check whether the service updates its features frequently while listening to customer feedback. For instance, WeVPN&rsquo;s development had been stopped for a year. Not surprising. On the other hand, I trust <a href="https://bearblog.dev/">Bear Blog</a> because I can see that Herman, Bear Blog&rsquo;s founder, has been dedicated to his philosophy of <a href="https://herman.bearblog.dev/building-software-to-last-forever/">building the service to last forever</a>.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s difficult to be up-to-date with every software. The easiest way to protect oneself from this kind of incident would be following individuals who&rsquo;re genuinely passionate about sharing quality information. For example, it&rsquo;s been helpful to follow <a href="https://theprivacydad.com/">The Privacy Dad</a> to learn more about online privacy. Thanks to him, I&rsquo;m now subscribed to a more reliable service.</p>
<p><em>Who should I follow? Email me if you have recommendations.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Watched Beef</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-15/</guid>
      <description>Today, I watched the last episode of a Netflix series, Beef.&#xA;Almost all characters inside struggle with depression, loneliness, or anger. Money doesn&amp;rsquo;t solve any of these problems. Getting parents&amp;rsquo; approval, raising a child, believing in God, meeting a therapist, and starting new relationships don&amp;rsquo;t help either.&#xA;For Danny(Steven Yeun) and Amy(Ali Wong), self-remedy begins when they decide to be fully vulnerable in front of their beloved ones. Danny to his younger brother and Amy to her husband; the two characters confess their unforgivable mistakes.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today, I watched the last episode of a Netflix series, Beef.</p>
<p>Almost all characters inside struggle with depression, loneliness, or anger. Money doesn&rsquo;t solve any of these problems. Getting parents&rsquo; approval, raising a child, believing in God, meeting a therapist, and starting new relationships don&rsquo;t help either.</p>
<p>For Danny(Steven Yeun) and Amy(Ali Wong), self-remedy begins when they decide to be fully vulnerable in front of their beloved ones. Danny to his younger brother and Amy to her husband; the two characters confess their unforgivable mistakes.</p>
<p>Unveiling the ugly truth creates a mess. Danny and Amy both lose the trust of the people they care about the most. Regardless of these consequences, Danny and Amy feel relieved because they no longer have to lie anymore. They&rsquo;re finally free from the obsession with perfectionism.</p>
<p>I wonder if I&rsquo;m making the same mistakes as Danny and Amy. Do I want other people to think I&rsquo;m flawless? Once in a while, it might be helpful to check if I&rsquo;m desperately pretending to be someone else.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make Something Wonderful</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-14/</guid>
      <description>There’s lots of ways to be, as a person. And some people express their deep appreciation in different ways. But one of the ways that I believe people express their appreciation to the rest of humanity is to make something wonderful and put it out there. - Steve Jobs&#xA;When I was looking for a job, I never thought I was capable of creating my own product. I could only imagine becoming a product manager at a fast-growing startup in Seoul.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>There’s lots of ways to be, as a person. And some people express their deep appreciation in different ways. But one of the ways that I believe people express their appreciation to the rest of humanity is to make something wonderful and put it out there. - Steve Jobs</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When I was looking for a job, I never thought I was capable of creating my own product. I could only imagine becoming a product manager at a fast-growing startup in Seoul.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s only been three years, but my life&rsquo;s totally different from what I envisioned. I run a restaurant with my wife and serve sandwiches for a living. This change could sound like a downgrade from an office job, but we always tell each other we&rsquo;re the happiest couple on earth.</p>
<p>Every day, customers from all over the world visit our restaurant. Not because we have Michelin stars but because <a href="https://www.happycow.net/reviews/cheesylazy-jeju-295726">everything we serve is vegan</a>. Many of them express how hard it was to follow a vegan/vegetarian diet in Jeju and tell us their appreciation for what we&rsquo;re doing. When we hear this kind of customer feedback, we realize our business is creating a positive impact on our community.</p>
<p>In addition to running a restaurant, we also write a weekly newsletter on <a href="https://cheesylazy.com/">our website</a>. Here, we share our thoughts, recipes, and tips for free. The website is not just a hobby. As much as we care about serving great food, we care about creating high-quality content. That&rsquo;s why we&rsquo;ve published more than 80 posts in a year.</p>
<p>We&rsquo;ve seen people using our recipes for their restaurants or parties. We&rsquo;ve read heartfelt comments saying our writings inspired them to be more authentic to themselves. Through our website, we&rsquo;ve also met small business owners from all over the country. Even though these people have never visited our restaurant, we&rsquo;ve built meaningful relationships with them.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m doing my part for humanity by making something wonderful.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical Thinking and Problem-Solving</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-13/</guid>
      <description>When writing college applications, I noticed that all universities preached the importance of critical thinking and problem-solving. I didn&amp;rsquo;t even understand what those skills meant, but I hoped getting a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree would help me to become an original thinker.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s been six years since I graduated from college, and I&amp;rsquo;m still unsure if I can think critically to solve complex problems. Without a doubt, I&amp;rsquo;ve realized a bubble filled with similar people is possibly the worst environment to learn &amp;ldquo;how to think.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When writing college applications, I noticed that all universities preached the importance of critical thinking and problem-solving. I didn&rsquo;t even understand what those skills meant, but I hoped getting a bachelor&rsquo;s degree would help me to become an original thinker.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s been six years since I graduated from college, and I&rsquo;m still unsure if I can think critically to solve complex problems. Without a doubt, I&rsquo;ve realized a bubble filled with similar people is possibly the worst environment to learn &ldquo;how to think.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can My Restaurant Survive?</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-12/</guid>
      <description>Since last week, my restaurant&amp;rsquo;s had a lot more customers than I expected. Am I grateful? Yes. Am I excited? Of course. Am I worried as well? 100%.&#xA;Because my wife and I are the only ones running the restaurant, the service tends to get sloppy when people rush in simultaneously. We always try our best to interact with the customers; however, when the orders get stacked, we become sandwich-making robots grilling veggies and pouring drinks as fast as possible.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since last week, my restaurant&rsquo;s had a lot more customers than I expected. Am I grateful? Yes. Am I excited? Of course. Am I worried as well? 100%.</p>
<p>Because my wife and I are the only ones running the restaurant, the service tends to get sloppy when people rush in simultaneously. We always try our best to interact with the customers; however, when the orders get stacked, we become sandwich-making robots grilling veggies and pouring drinks as fast as possible.</p>
<p>We never wanted CHEESYLAZY(our sandwich shop) to be another version of McDonald&rsquo;s. Selling more sandwiches and making more money was never our motto. We wanted to start a &ldquo;too small to fail&rdquo; type of business so that we could forget about the &ldquo;growth at all costs&rdquo; mentality. That&rsquo;s why we spent months searching for the cheapest property.</p>
<p>More time invested into the restaurant means less time for learning and relaxing. When the number of guests doubles, we must put much more time into prepping ingredients and cleaning dishes. This means I&rsquo;ll be too tired to spend enough time writing my daily post on this blog. I won&rsquo;t be able to have enough playtime with my cats, and I won&rsquo;t be able to finish reading any books on my Kindle. Suddenly, my life gets very boring.</p>
<p>Again, I&rsquo;m beyond grateful to see so many people in our restaurant. We used to have 3 guests per day, so things are much better now. However, I wonder if the restaurant will be able to survive if we continue beating ourselves to serve more customers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Smile to Strangers</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-11/</guid>
      <description>At my restaurant, I meet two kinds of people: the ones who smile and those who never smile.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s joyful to serve the first group of people. They&amp;rsquo;re the reason why I love this job. When these visitors open the door, the space brightens instantly. I feel so lucky to have such guests at the restaurant every day.&#xA;Dealing with the second group of people is a bit tricky. These people treat restaurant workers like ordering machines.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At <a href="https://www.happycow.net/reviews/cheesylazy-jeju-295726">my restaurant</a>, I meet two kinds of people: the ones who smile and those who never smile.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s joyful to serve the first group of people. They&rsquo;re the reason why I love this job. When these visitors open the door, the space brightens instantly. I feel so lucky to have such guests at the restaurant every day.</p>
<p>Dealing with the second group of people is a bit tricky. These people treat restaurant workers like ordering machines. I say hello, thank you, and goodbye but no answers. The restaurant is often merely a prop for their Instagram. I try to be indifferent, but it&rsquo;s not that easy to be 100% positive.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;d like to belong to the first group. Not only inside a restaurant but everywhere I meet strangers. Smiling has the power to make someone&rsquo;s day better. Why not use it?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who Cares?</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/2023-04-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/2023-04-09/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve published every day this week. The work&amp;rsquo;s been busy, but I still spent a couple hours before sleep to publish a new post.&#xA;I feel great that I&amp;rsquo;m actually writing instead of complaining about how I want to &amp;ldquo;create more instead of watching Netflix.&amp;rdquo; At the same time, I&amp;rsquo;m a little worried this blog would only be seen as my personal diary.&#xA;What should the readers expect from this website?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.kangminsuk.com/blog/1/">I&rsquo;ve published every day</a> this week. The work&rsquo;s been busy, but I still spent a couple hours before sleep to publish a new post.</p>
<p>I feel great that I&rsquo;m actually writing instead of complaining about how I want to &ldquo;create more instead of watching Netflix.&rdquo; At the same time, I&rsquo;m a little worried this blog would only be seen as my personal diary.</p>
<p>What should the readers expect from this website? What would be the reason to subscribe to my writings? Do these questions even matter?</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s a conundrum. It&rsquo;s difficult to write without thinking about other people&rsquo;s opinions. I publish whatever I can think of but still want you to think I&rsquo;m a smart guy sharing something useful.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dear Ryuichi Sakamoto</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-08/</guid>
      <description>Your music used to be my only friend.&#xA;I had recently moved to the U.S. with my sisters. I was a 9th grader back then. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know how to speak English or have any friends. I always had a stern face and ate alone in the cafeteria. Sometimes, I skipped lunch and hid in the school bathroom. I was terrified of being alone.&#xA;From where I lived, getting to the school took about an hour and a half.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Your music used to be my only friend.</p>
<p>I had recently moved to the U.S. with my sisters. I was a 9th grader back then. I didn&rsquo;t know how to speak English or have any friends. I always had a stern face and ate alone in the cafeteria. Sometimes, I skipped lunch and hid in the school bathroom. I was terrified of being alone.</p>
<p>From where I lived, getting to the school took about an hour and a half. I had to wake up at 5:30 to catch an old minivan. When I hopped in the car, I took my iPod Mini out and played the first track of your album <em>Playing the Piano</em>.</p>
<p>I closed my eyes and listened to you playing piano. I could even hear you stepping on the pedals. I felt like your music understood what I was feeling. I was an angry kid who occasionally went outside the apartment to scream as loud as he could. No one could dare, but you let me calm down and find peace.</p>
<p>I wish I could tell you how grateful I am. Your music changed my life.</p>
<p>Rest in peace, Ryuichi Sakamoto.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Don&#39;t Have to Be the Best</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-07/</guid>
      <description>Lots of self-help books love to talk about the importance of mastering one&amp;rsquo;s craft. &amp;ldquo;Find your niche and be the best&amp;rdquo; might be the most general advice on the Internet.&#xA;What does &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; mean anyway? I&amp;rsquo;m a restaurant owner and blogger. Do I have to be a world-famous restauranteur and writer to be considered successful? Or is becoming the country&amp;rsquo;s favorite enough? How about the best in town? Being the most talented baker in my family wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be satisfying, right?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lots of self-help books love to talk about the importance of mastering one&rsquo;s craft. &ldquo;Find your niche and be the best&rdquo; might be the most general advice on the Internet.</p>
<p>What does &ldquo;best&rdquo; mean anyway? I&rsquo;m a restaurant owner and blogger. Do I have to be a world-famous restauranteur and writer to be considered successful? Or is becoming the country&rsquo;s favorite enough? How about the best in town? Being the most talented baker in my family wouldn&rsquo;t be satisfying, right?</p>
<p>Not everyone can be Serena Williams at their job. Metrics for success should feel manageable. It takes time, but knowing one&rsquo;s values might be the most rewarding endeavor.</p>
<p>Discovering the works of David Chang and Salman Rushdie should not make me feel small. No one&rsquo;s asking me to mimic their lives. My life&rsquo;s all set as long as I&rsquo;m curious, optimistic, and peaceful.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t have to be called &ldquo;the best&rdquo; to be happy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m in Love With This World</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/23-04-06/</guid>
      <description>This quote from John Green&amp;rsquo;s The Anthropocene Reviewed resonated with me.&#xA;I cry a lot because I miss people. I cry a lot because they die, and I can&amp;rsquo;t stop them. They leave me, and I love them more. I&amp;rsquo;m finding out as I&amp;rsquo;m aging that I&amp;rsquo;m in love with the world. - Maurice Sendak&#xA;My life&amp;rsquo;s already successful.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m too lucky to have beautiful relationships with my wife, family, and friends.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This quote from John Green&rsquo;s <em>The Anthropocene Reviewed</em> resonated with me.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I cry a lot because I miss people. I cry a lot because they die, and I can&rsquo;t stop them. They leave me, and I love them more. I&rsquo;m finding out as I&rsquo;m aging that I&rsquo;m in love with the world. - Maurice Sendak</p>
</blockquote>
<p>My life&rsquo;s already successful.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m too lucky to have beautiful relationships with my wife, family, and friends. How about the customers who leave thank you notes at my restaurant? How about my two lovely cats sleeping next to me? The fact that you&rsquo;re reading this from all over the world is a miracle.</p>
<p>I need to make sure my mind doesn&rsquo;t fall into a nasty trap. It&rsquo;s so easy to dismiss the world&rsquo;s wonders. Once in a while, I need to look around. I&rsquo;m in love with this world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dad Walks Into My Restaurant</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/4/</guid>
      <description>Grief never ends.&#xA;My father passed away three months after my wife and I opened our little sandwich shop.&#xA;My mother had only one wish: to visit their son&amp;rsquo;s restaurant with her husband. However, Dad was unable to recover from major surgeries. He died without seeing his son&amp;rsquo;s biggest achievement.&#xA;After Dad&amp;rsquo;s passing, I put pictures of him around the restaurant. For example, one of his old identification photos is next to the ovens I use every morning.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Grief never ends.</p>
<p>My father passed away three months after my wife and I opened our little sandwich shop.</p>
<p>My mother had only one wish: to visit their son&rsquo;s restaurant with her husband. However, Dad was unable to recover from major surgeries. He died without seeing his son&rsquo;s biggest achievement.</p>
<p>After Dad&rsquo;s passing, I put pictures of him around the restaurant. For example, one of his old identification photos is next to the ovens I use every morning.</p>
<p>In the photo, he looks healthy, spirited, and ambitious. Whenever I gaze at his face, I realize he was younger than me when he had his first child. At my age, he could never dream of starting his own business. For the family, he had to put aside his dreams.</p>
<p>When he got married to Mom, both of them planned to go study in another country. The bigger world was their destination. They believed leaving Korea would be a wise choice for their future.</p>
<p>The couple couldn&rsquo;t study abroad as they wished. However, 20 years later, all of their children had a chance to be educated in the United States. Their dreams came true based on a generation of effort.</p>
<p>Dad is gone, but I often imagine him walking into the restaurant. &ldquo;This is the best sandwich I&rsquo;ve ever had.&rdquo; He gives me a signature thumbs-up. I smile back and hug him to say thank you. Soon, our interaction ends, and I confront reality.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Last Glance at You</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/3/</guid>
      <description>Inside a hospital, Shinjae was facing death. His liver cancer had now spread to the spine, lungs, and brain.&#xA;A few days ago, his fever became so high that his wife had no choice but to call an ambulance. The trip to the hospital felt like a one-way road; everyone in the car knew that he would not be able to come back to his own house.&#xA;People around Shinjae used to praise his relentless optimism.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Inside a hospital, Shinjae was facing death. His liver cancer had now spread to the spine, lungs, and brain.</p>
<p>A few days ago, his fever became so high that his wife had no choice but to call an ambulance. The trip to the hospital felt like a one-way road; everyone in the car knew that he would not be able to come back to his own house.</p>
<p>People around Shinjae used to praise his relentless optimism. However, lying on a bed for two months while undergoing two dangerous surgeries transformed him into a dejected pessimist. No one could blame him for the dramatic change.</p>
<p>&ldquo;I can&rsquo;t remember things clearly,&rdquo; Shinjae told the nurse beside him. Ever since the first surgery to remove tumors on the spine, at least five different drugs had filled his body. A patch on his chest, daily injections, and narcotic medications were potent but insufficient to keep him at peace.</p>
<p>Past few days, Shinjae had many visitors. His brother, sisters, and friends all had to hold tears because they sensed it would be their last chance to be with him.</p>
<p>Shinjae could hardly eat, talk, or think. However, he somehow managed to tell the visitors a few words. &ldquo;My great hero,&rdquo; Shinjae said to his younger brother. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m happy to see you,&rdquo; he told his old friend.</p>
<p>Shinjae&rsquo;s children took turns spending a night with him. Every night, a child cared for him suffering from fever, hiccups, and sputum. Shinjae barely talked, and his jaundiced eyes could not see much. He still nodded slightly to communicate appreciation for the children&rsquo;s presence.</p>
<p>The time was coming to an end. His doctor suggested that the disease was incurable, and he would now be required to move to a hospice facility in two weeks. The family wished to keep him in the same room, but the hospital mandated all patients to clear the space in four weeks.</p>
<p>&ldquo;The hospice facility has a terrible reputation. I don&rsquo;t want my dad to spend his last moment inside a cramped room.&rdquo; Shinjae&rsquo;s son said to the caregiver next to him. The son could not bear that the doctor would send the dying patient to a worse environment. His father&rsquo;s life deserved much more respect than that.</p>
<p>Under the influence of strong painkillers, Shinjae could nonetheless hear the conversation between his son and the caregiver. His finger twitched a little bit. He had to choose while he could.</p>
<p>Shinjae felt his heartbeat and began to hold his breath. He mustered all of the energy to turn his head and took a last glance at his son. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m sorry,&rdquo; Shinjae said quietly to everyone he could think of.</p>
<p>The monitor began to make a noise, and a nurse entered the room to check his vital signs. The son couldn&rsquo;t do anything but tremble. Shinjae was now free from cancer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creators Over Consumers</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/2/</guid>
      <description>Artists work while critics complain. I have the utmost respect for those who are passionate about perfecting their creations.&#xA;I look up to doers, not talkers. I&amp;rsquo;m not impressed by your Rolex either. That&amp;rsquo;s why I get fascinated by the stories of entrepreneurs, chefs, and writers.&#xA;As a restaurant owner, I hear tons of unwanted advice from random family members and guests. Not a single one of them has any experience running a restaurant, but all of them are so sure about their suggestions.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>
<p>Artists work while critics complain. I have the utmost respect for those who are passionate about perfecting their creations.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I look up to doers, not talkers. I&rsquo;m not impressed by your Rolex either. That&rsquo;s why I get fascinated by the stories of entrepreneurs, chefs, and writers.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>As a restaurant owner, I hear tons of unwanted advice from random family members and guests. Not a single one of them has any experience running a restaurant, but all of them are so sure about their suggestions. I try my best to ignore what they say so that I can surround myself with great books and podcasts.</p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve Decided to Write Every Day</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/1/</guid>
      <description>“Give up trying to create something sophisticated,” I told myself. “Why not forget all those prescriptive ideas about ‘the novel’ and ‘literature’ and set down your feelings and thoughts as they come to you, freely, in a way that you like?” - Haruki Murakami&#xA;I believe in the art of persistence.&#xA;From now on, I&amp;rsquo;ll be publishing every single day. Mostly in English, but occasionally in Korean. No overarching theme.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>“Give up trying to create something sophisticated,” I told myself. “Why not forget all those prescriptive ideas about ‘the novel’ and ‘literature’ and set down your feelings and thoughts as they come to you, freely, in a way that you like?” - <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2022/nov/05/i-want-to-open-a-window-in-their-souls-haruki-murakami-on-the-power-of-writing-simply">Haruki Murakami</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>I believe in the art of persistence.</p>
<p>From now on, I&rsquo;ll be publishing every single day. Mostly in English, but occasionally in Korean. No overarching theme. Whatever jumps to my mind, I&rsquo;ll jot it down on this blog.</p>
<p>It doesn&rsquo;t matter if the day&rsquo;s writing is god-awful. This project is for my own benefit. Without this system, I&rsquo;ll always find an excuse to lie on my bed and start doom-scrolling until my thumb hurts.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s time to wake up and create. This is the change my heart demands.</p>
<p>See you tomorrow.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Problem With Upbit, the Largest Crypto Exchange in Korea</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/upbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/upbit/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, the biggest crypto exchange in South Korea, Upbit rejected my requests to move the coins to my personal wallet.&#xA;Here&amp;rsquo;s a timeline of what happened.&#xA;I decided to move all my crypto on Upbit to another wallet. No special reason. Just never really liked storing all my assets in the exchange. Can say that I was inspired by &amp;ldquo;not your keys, not your coins&amp;rdquo; ethos. On Upbit, I had withdrawn ~$3,000 total worth of ETH, BTC, SOL, MATIC, LINK.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, the biggest crypto exchange in South Korea, Upbit rejected my requests to move the coins to my personal wallet.</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s a timeline of what happened.</p>
<ul>
<li>I decided to move all my crypto on Upbit to another wallet. No special reason. Just never really liked storing all my assets in the exchange. Can say that I was inspired by &ldquo;not your keys, not your coins&rdquo; ethos.</li>
<li>On Upbit, I had withdrawn ~$3,000 total worth of ETH, BTC, SOL, MATIC, LINK. However, Upbit refused to approve my transactions. I waited a while, but the status kept saying &ldquo;pending.&rdquo;</li>
<li>A manager from Upbit called me to verify my requests. Initially thought it was just another layer of security. He checked whether I could verify my name, birthday, email, and home address. Additionally, he asked me why I was moving my assets and to which address I&rsquo;m sending them. I was a little annoyed about these questions but told him honestly that I just decided to store my coins in a personal wallet. Then he asked me multiple times whether I was being duped to send the assets to an unknown address. I said there was nothing to worry about. The manager replied that he would be sharing the info with another team to make sure Upbit can confirm the validity of the requests. I said sure and the call ended.</li>
<li>After a few minutes, Upbit sent me a message saying I needed to sign a legal waiver form, take a picture with it (showing my face), and submit the photo to Upbit&rsquo;s customer support channel if I wanted to send my currencies to another wallet.</li>
</ul>
<p>As of 2023, Upbit owns about <a href="https://www.etoday.co.kr/news/view/2231722">80%</a> of the regulated crypto market in S. Korea. Koreans have stored billions of dollars worth of assets without realizing that the exchange could easily deny the transfer of their own assets. I understand that there are lots of scams and criminal activities happening, and Upbit has the responsibility to prevent any malicious attempts. However, that does not mean that all users must be forced to sign a legal document and take a picture with it. Transferring one&rsquo;s own money should not be this difficult.</p>
<p>From this experience, I have learned one important lesson. For Upbit, all of its depositors are now potential criminals. To truly own your crypto, I advise you to first get your coins off the exchange.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Job at a Time</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/one-job-at-a-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/one-job-at-a-time/</guid>
      <description>My brain can&amp;rsquo;t function like a web browser. I need to stop running 5 different tabs in my mind.&#xA;I find myself getting anxious when I&amp;rsquo;m focusing on one job at a moment. I have to listen to a podcast while walking, read an article while sipping coffee, and watch YouTube while playing with cats. It seems like my brain has learned to fake maximum productivity all the time.&#xA;Why can&amp;rsquo;t I just do one job at a time?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My brain can&rsquo;t function like a web browser. I need to stop running 5 different tabs in my mind.</p>
<p>I find myself getting anxious when I&rsquo;m focusing on one job at a moment. I have to listen to a podcast while walking, read an article while sipping coffee, and watch YouTube while playing with cats. It seems like my brain has learned to fake maximum productivity all the time.</p>
<p>Why can&rsquo;t I just do one job at a time? It must be so easy to pay full attention to simple acts like walking, watching, and eating. However, it&rsquo;s painfully difficult to be 100% aware of the present moment.</p>
<p>Maybe social media is to blame, but I&rsquo;m the one responsible to take care of my mind&rsquo;s well-being. I&rsquo;m the one in charge of fixing bad habits and constructing better systems.</p>
<p>So, I&rsquo;ve made a few promises myself to be more human and less computer-like.</p>
<ul>
<li>Stop switching. Finish the job before moving on to a new one.</li>
<li>Be aware of the addiction. Notice the urge to check &rsquo;likes&rsquo; and &lsquo;comments.&rsquo; Tech products have become drugs, and I hate to be an addict.</li>
<li>Consume long-form content. My attention span should be capable of understanding a book instead of a tweet.</li>
</ul>
<p>As Anthony De Mello <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Awareness-Opportunities-Reality-Anthony-Mello/dp/0385249373">says</a>, &ldquo;You become happy by contact with reality. That&rsquo;s what brings happiness, a moment-by-moment contact with reality.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StarCraft - It&#39;s Not Just a Game</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/starcraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/starcraft/</guid>
      <description>StarCraft is more than just a game When I was in elementary school, every single guy in my class was in love with this computer game called StarCraft. I remember rushing to a PC bang every day after school to spend hours and hours playing the game. The parents weren’t so happy, but StarCraft was bigger than any other sport. It felt like a requirement to make friends in school.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663336203.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<h3 id="starcraft-is-more-than-just-a-game">StarCraft is more than just a game</h3>
<p>When I was in elementary school, every single guy in my class was in love with this computer game called StarCraft. I remember rushing to a PC bang every day after school to spend hours and hours playing the game. The parents weren’t so happy, but StarCraft was bigger than any other sport. It felt like a requirement to make friends in school.</p>
<p>Professional gamers like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lim_Yo-hwan">Lim Yo-hwan</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nal_rA">Kang Min</a> were my idols. I wanted to play like them, so I even “studied” their strategies to be a better player than my friends. Unfortunately, I don’t think I was considered “a good StarCraft player” in school (I was just about the average). Too many kids were putting serious effort into the game.</p>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663336273.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<p><strong>At the 2005 StarCraft League Final in Busan.</strong></p>
<p>If you’ve played games like League of Legends and Overwatch, you’ve probably seen Koreans winning Esports championships. So, instead of talking about the great players like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Faker_(gamer)">Faker</a>, I’d like to unravel the unprecedented success of StarCraft in Korea.</p>
<h3 id="korean-financial-crisis">Korean financial crisis</h3>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663336330.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<p>During the first half of the 1990s, the South Korean economy was growing at about 5~8% every year. Lots of “experts” were optimistic about the country’s economy in the future.</p>
<p>However, in 1997, the country faced a load of economic problems during <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1997_Asian_financial_crisis">the Asian financial crisis</a> — Major companies and banks had to file for bankruptcy and millions of people lost their jobs due to the economic instability.</p>
<p>Wait, why talk about the financial crisis? Because it allowed PC bang to spread all over the country. Those who got kicked out of their companies still had to do something to make ends meet. And lots of them chose to open up a PC bang because it only required an empty space full of computers and chairs. It definitely seemed like a safer investment than owning a restaurant.</p>
<p>In addition, because PC bang charged about 1,000 won (~$1) per hour, playing games at PC bang was one of the cheapest options for entertainment. Despite the devastating consequences, the financial crisis enabled the PC bangs to reach all corners. In just 4 years after the crisis, there were more than 20,000 PC bangs around the country.</p>
<h3 id="starcraft-meets-pc-bang">StarCraft meets PC bang</h3>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663336395.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<p><strong>PC bang in the early 1990s.</strong></p>
<p>StarCraft’s rising popularity was the core engine behind the PC bangs’ success. Back then, 9 out of 10 people in PC bangs were playing StarCraft. PC bangs existed for a single game, and StarCraft benefited from this relationship. For StarCraft, there was no need for advertisements or promotions, PC bangs were serving as the game&rsquo;s unofficial PR agency.</p>
<h3 id="other-reasons">Other reasons</h3>
<p>There were several other elements that contributed to StarCraft’s mega-success:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>StarCraft’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle.net">Battle.net</a> capability could really flourish under the Korean government’s aggressive investment into a high-speed internet network. If you’ve never heard of Battle.net, it basically enabled gamers to play against each other through the Internet. The feature sounds like common sense today, but it revolutionized the gaming culture in Korea. It’s a lot more interesting when you can play with an actual person instead of a bot.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>In 1999 after the financial crisis, TV producer Hwang Hyeong-jun chose to host a StarCraft competition on TV for the first time in the world. Hwang <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MAd1_YfiVL8">says</a> that almost all shows had to stop producing because of the budget cut, but he realized “game broadcasts didn’t require much production fees.” After Hwang’s decision, the StarCraft league in Korea continued for 13 years on channels like On Game Net. For 13 years, game channels were the backbone of StarCraft&rsquo;s popularity.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A number of players proved that playing for an Esports team is just like playing for a professional soccer team. Especially some players like Lim Yo-hwan became so famous that people said “Even if you’ve never played StarCraft, you know who Lim is.” Because of these star players, there were rivalries, dramas, and stories in the leagues. People still talk about the great rivalry between Lim and Hong Jin-ho.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>If you’re curious to know more about Esports in Korea, I highly recommend watching this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MAd1_YfiVL8">documentary</a> on YouTube.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hiking Clothing in South Korea</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/hiking-clothing-in-south-korea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/hiking-clothing-in-south-korea/</guid>
      <description>Hiking in Korea Mountains are everywhere in S. Korea — according to the Korea Forest Service (산림청), Korea has 4,440 mountains in its territory. Do Koreans like visiting these mountains though? The answer is HELL YEAH.&#xA;Koreans visit the mountains for many reasons: to exercise, sightsee, and even socialize. Anywhere from Gangwon to Jeju, hiking is arguably one of the most popular activities in this country.&#xA;The hiking outfits are not just for hiking Even if it’s your first time visiting Korea, it’d only take a few hours to notice how common these hiking clothes are.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663335631.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<h3 id="hiking-in-korea">Hiking in Korea</h3>
<p>Mountains are everywhere in S. Korea — according to <a href="https://news.mt.co.kr/mtview.php?no=2007121315390529831#:~:text=%EC%82%B0%EB%A6%BC%EC%B2%AD%EC%9D%80%20%EC%9E%91%EB%85%84%2010%EC%9B%94,%EC%A1%B0%EC%82%AC%EB%90%90%EB%8B%A4%EA%B3%A0%2013%EC%9D%BC%20%EB%B0%9D%ED%98%94%EB%8B%A4">the Korea Forest Service (산림청)</a>, Korea has 4,440 mountains in its territory. Do Koreans like visiting these mountains though? The answer is HELL YEAH.</p>
<p>Koreans visit the mountains for many reasons: to exercise, sightsee, and even socialize. Anywhere from Gangwon to Jeju, hiking is arguably one of the most popular activities in this country.</p>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663335681.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<h3 id="the-hiking-outfits-are-not-just-for-hiking">The hiking outfits are not just for hiking</h3>
<p>Even if it’s your first time visiting Korea, it’d only take a few hours to notice how common these hiking clothes are. Especially for many middle-aged ajummas and ajeossis, bright jackets and active pants have been their favorite outfits.</p>
<p>However, some people are not too proud of this unique culture among middle-aged Koreans. For example, a travel agency <a href="http://www.asiae.co.kr/news/view.htm?idxno=2016042008573883662">asked</a> Korean tourists to “avoid wearing hiking clothes in the beautiful cities of Europe.” I personally think the fashion is awesome. Why would you think it’s embarrassing?</p>
<p>Anyways, Korea’s outdoor fashion market is considered the second biggest in the world. Particularly from 2004 to 2014, the market size grew from less than US$ 500 million to US$ 6 billion.</p>
<p>Above all, The North Face had <a href="https://news.mt.co.kr/mtview.php?no=2021031614053731106">the biggest success</a> during this period — reporting US$ 500 million in yearly revenue from 2011 to 2014.</p>
<h3 id="the-force-behind-the-north-faces-success">The force behind The North Face’s success</h3>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663335766.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<p>The North Face was ahead of the game because its style appealed to teens and 20s. For example, in the early 2010s, the brand’s goose down and puffer jackets were so popular that teens were wearing them as their school uniforms.</p>
<p>However, the jackets’ enormous popularity among teenagers became a widespread <a href="http://monthly.chosun.com/client/news/viw.asp?ctcd=E&amp;nNewsNumb=201203100042">concern</a> in society. There were reports that the students who couldn’t afford the jacket were getting bullied in school. In another case, a 15-year-old boy was dragged and got beaten by five other teens who wanted to steal the jacket.</p>
<p>It’s hard to believe, but buying a jacket somehow became a matter of survival in some schools.</p>
<h3 id="how-much-is-your-jacket">How much is your jacket?</h3>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663335840.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<p>The news about “The North Face Hierarchy” in middle schools forced tons of parents to buy these US$ 200~700 jackets for their children. Clearly, for many teenagers, the jacket meant more than just clothing — it was a brand-new symbol of wealth and status.</p>
<p>Some people argued that Korea’s highly competitive education system made teens obsessed with anything that boosts one’s self-esteem. But the education system cannot be the sole reason. Kids learn fast from the adults around them.</p>
<p>One time I was in an indoor pool and overheard a conversation between two little teenagers. I was shocked because they were talking about the price of their houses and the future of Seoul&rsquo;s real estate market.</p>
<p>I’m sure these teens weren’t genuinely interested in the housing market. They observed their parents and simply learned from them to play the same status game.</p>
<h3 id="when-one-thought-spending--for-a-jacket-seemed-too-much">When one thought spending $$$ for a jacket seemed too much…</h3>
<p>Let’s talk about Moncler’s success in Korea. In 2012, a picture of President Lee Myung-bak’s granddaughter wearing an expensive <a href="https://biz.chosun.com/site/data/html_dir/2012/01/24/2012012400735.html">Moncler jacket</a> became a viral topic in the media. <a href="http://www.newspeak.kr/news/articleView.html?idxno=18498">Hundreds of articles</a> were titled ‘The Grand Daughter of Lee Ends The North Face Hierarchy.”</p>
<p>Since then, Moncler’s yearly revenue grew from around US$ 40 million to US$ 130 million in 2019. In department stores, Moncler puffer jackets, at US$ 2,500, often get sold out in September (Korea gets cold in November).</p>
<p>Back to the real hiking clothes. “The North Face Hierarchy” has vanished since 2015. At the same time, the outdoor fashion market in Korea has shrunk to about US$ 3 billion. The situation seems pretty dire, but outdoor clothing brands are still trying hard to attract young customers.</p>
<h3 id="millennials-are-interested-in-hiking">Millennials are interested in hiking</h3>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663335949.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<p>Due to COVID-19, many Koreans could not go to indoor gyms and other sports facilities for a long time. Just like almost every in the world today, Koreans were getting quarantine fatigue.</p>
<p>To overcome the tiredness, more Koreans began to visit the mountains to take a walk and get some fresh air. In 2020, the Korea Park Service published that the number of visitors to major mountains like Bukhansan in Seoul <a href="https://www.lak.co.kr/m/news/view.php?id=9439">increased by 20 percent</a>.</p>
<p>Black Yak, a Korean outdoor clothing brand, knew this was a great opportunity. Black Yak created an online hiking community called “Black Yak Alpine Club” and released an app that lets users share pictures of the mountains.</p>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663335993.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<p>Black Yak Alpine Club has been a great success — In 2020, there were about 40,000 members, and the number became more than 200,000 members after a year. The brand has also created viral content like “100 Best Mountains of Korea” to challenge hikers to visit and post pictures of all of them.</p>
<p>This year, Black Yak is expected to generate more revenue than The North Face to become the biggest outdoor clothing brand in Korea. Thanks to this new trend, hiking is no longer for ajummas and ajeossis only.</p>
<p>Due to the influx of Millennials, outdoor fashion is evolving to embrace leggings and tights. For example, Black Yak’s hiking clothes look like workout clothes from Nike or Adidas Originals.</p>
<h3 id="ps-skip-seoul-tower-visit-a-mountain">P.S. Skip Seoul Tower, visit a mountain</h3>
<p>About 5 years ago, I was a part-time worker at the famous N Seoul Tower. I enjoyed interacting with tourists from all over the world, but I also thought visiting the tower was the most “unKorean” thing you can do as a tourist.</p>
<p>If my friend’s visiting Korea for the first time, I would recommend skipping the famous attractions (except Gyeongbokgung maybe) and go to the mountains like Bukhansan or Chenggyesan.</p>
<p>Take the subway to get there in the morning and buy some Gimbap and water before hiking. You don’t even need to know the route. Just follow the pros wearing bright jackets and hiking shoes. Stumble upon a Buddhist temple and make a wish in front of stone stacks.</p>
<p>After the long hike, don’t forget to finish off the day with some makgeolli and jeon.</p>
<p>Trust me. Skip the damn tower and visit the mountains.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baek Jong-won - the Most Famous Entrepreneur in Korea</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/baek-jong-won/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/baek-jong-won/</guid>
      <description>If I had to guess the most famous entrepreneur in Korea, I would say it’s Baek Jong-won.&#xA;If you’ve never heard of him; Baek Jong-won is the founder of an international restaurant company called The Born. The Born is a major player in the South Korean dining market with over 20 brands and 1,500 restaurants.1&#xA;There’s no doubt that Baek is an outstanding businessperson. Fast-casual Korean, BBQ, Korean Chinese, bibimbap, Udon, etc.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If I had to guess the most famous entrepreneur in Korea, I would say it’s Baek Jong-won.</p>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663334256.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<p>If you’ve never heard of him; Baek Jong-won is the founder of an international restaurant company called <a href="https://www.theborn.co.kr/">The Born</a>. The Born is a major player in the South Korean dining market with over 20 brands and 1,500 restaurants.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
<p>There’s no doubt that Baek is an outstanding businessperson. Fast-casual Korean, BBQ, Korean Chinese, bibimbap, Udon, etc. You name a popular cuisine in Korea and the guy has created a successful brand already.</p>
<p>However, Baek’s restaurants are only a fraction of his far-reaching influence in Korea. To really understand him, we need to talk about his recipes, TV show appearances, and even philosophy.</p>
<h3 id="recipes">Recipes</h3>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663334320.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>If chefs’ recipes are for professional cyclists, my recipes are like a bicycle with training wheels. - <a href="http://news.tf.co.kr/read/entertain/1550486.htm">Baek Jong-won</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Lots of Koreans, including myself, follow these steps when cooking a meal:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Choose what I want to eat.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Search for Baek’s recipe online.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>‘백종원 레시피’ (Baek Jong-won recipe) has become a genre itself. Why? Some notable characteristics, besides his likable personality, have contributed to the unprecedented success of his recipes.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p><em>Easy.</em>
No need for special ingredients and techniques. Baek’s recipes are meant to serve those who are unfamiliar with cooking. In other words, Baek doesn’t give a shit about “a proper way to cut an onion” or “the healthiest meal for you.” His goal is to teach you the easiest way to cook up some tasty food. For example, he never asks you to use “5 grams of minced garlic.” Baek just tells you to use “a spoon of minced garlic.” Is it the most precise method? No. But everyone can easily understand the recipes.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Affordable.</em>
Just like The Born’s restaurants that serve comfort food at cheap prices, Baek’s recipes never use a “gourmet” ingredient. You can follow most of his recipes with the ingredients available in convenient stores. He even releases a new recipe when a certain ingredient like green onions (대파) becomes extremely cheap due to the oversupply. That&rsquo;s why students follow his recipes religiously.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Reliable.</em>
Baek is not a chef but an incredible food researcher. The man has studied so much about food that he is known as a “walking food dictionary.” His vast knowledge about food history and restaurant business has enabled shows like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baek_Jong-won%27s_Alley_Restaurant"><em>Alley Restaurant</em></a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Street_Food_Fighter"><em>Street Food Fighter</em></a>.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Baek’s recipes from his <a href="https://www.aladin.co.kr/author/wauthor_overview.aspx?AuthorSearch=@1131486">books</a>, tv-shows, and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCyn-K7rZLXjGl7VXGweIlcA">YouTube</a> have inspired millions of people to stop ordering and start cooking. I would argue that his recipes are the biggest force that shapes Koreans’ eating habits.</p>
<h3 id="tv-shows">TV Shows</h3>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663334546.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>I’m not a celebrity. I’m a food entrepreneur. I appear on these TV shows because I want people to know more about the food they eat. When people understand how the food is made, they begin to appreciate what they order at restaurants. - <a href="https://www.chosun.com/entertainments/entertain_photo/2021/03/11/MIIAOCOFVHCBSLWT2UT2EGY364/">Baek Jong-won</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Baek doesn’t enjoy being a mega-famous celebrity in Korea, but he has never stopped appearing on TV since <a href="https://ko.wikipedia.org/wiki/%EC%A7%84%EC%A7%9C_%ED%95%9C%EA%B5%AD%EC%9D%98_%EB%A7%9B"><em>The Real Taste of Korea</em></a> first aired in 2010.</p>
<h3 id="the-media-is-baeks-powerful-leverage">The media is Baek’s powerful leverage</h3>
<p>Baek’s influence on Korean media began to skyrocket when he appeared on <em>My Little Television</em> on MBC in 2015.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> There were so many guests on the program, but Baek’s cooking show was the primary reason behind MLT’s success.</p>
<p>Just a few examples of Baek’s huge impact in 2015: Supermarkets ran out of minced pork when he came up with “<a href="https://www.beyondkimchee.com/mr-baeks-multi-purpose-soy-sauce/">multi-purpose soy sauce (만능간장)</a>,” the sales of canned fish <a href="https://it.chosun.com/site/data/html_dir/2015/07/15/2015071585067.html">increased by 14 times</a> when Baek introduced “canned fish recipes,” and The Born reported its 34% revenue growth.</p>
<p>After My Little Television’s enormous success, Baek continued to host shows such as The Homemade Food Master from 2015 to 2017, Alley Restaurant from 2018, and Street Food Fighter from 2018.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> No need to know what these shows are about. The argument here is that Baek is, in Korea, Gordon Ramsay in <em>Hell’s Kitchen</em> plus Anthony Bourdain in <em>Part Unknown</em>.</p>
<p>It’s now difficult to name one successful cooking show in Korea without the presence of Baek. In these shows, Baek is the one that helps restaurant owners to revitalize their business, promotes the consumption of overproduced farm products, and introduces unfamiliar cuisines around the world. He does it all and no one dares to replace him.</p>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663334796.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<p>Not just the TV shows though. When Baek started his YouTube Channel in 2019, he only needed <a href="https://www.chosun.com/entertainments/entertain_photo/2020/10/25/WHECZ77M2BM4PFL2PHNMNHNN5Y/">3 days</a> to reach a million subscribers (now at around 5 million). Baek’s YouTube videos mainly showcase his signature recipes (usually have subtitles in 5 different languages) and Baek’s advice for fellow restaurant owners.</p>
<p>He constantly says he is neither a chef nor a celebrity, and this belief has prevented him from appearing on shows that have nothing to do with food and restaurants. However, Baek understands the power of media as a leverage. Through the shows, books, and even <a href="http://www.yes24.com/Product/Goods/70917138">cartoons</a>, he’s become a man that cannot be introduced by a single title. He’s now simply known as Baek Jong-won.</p>
<h3 id="philosophy">Philosophy</h3>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663334864.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>You need direct experience to be really curious about the problem. Start small now and you’ll be able to find your uniqueness. - <a href="http://www.yes24.com/Product/Goods/30659754">Baek Jong-won</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>When Baek was only [9 years old]
(<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-IV35uxHaUc)">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-IV35uxHaUc)</a>, his dream was to become a wealthy mushroom farmer. When he was 12, he collected glasses with a handcart to sell them to a junk shop. Before starting college, he worked as a used car dealer. Before graduating college, he was already the owner of 3 different pubs.</p>
<p>Despite all the success, when Baek graduated from college, his family got so worried about his plan to take over a nightclub and eventually forced him to join the army to serve as an officer for 4 years.</p>
<p>Anyways, Baek’s career as a restauranteur finally began with a ssambap (Korean rice wraps) restaurant in 1993.<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup> At that time, Baek was not too serious about the restaurant business. Instead, he was more interested in becoming a world-class timber trader. Baek says, “I only wanted to make a lot of money.”</p>
<h3 id="failures">Failures</h3>
<p>After Baek had invested so much into the timber business, IMF financial crisis took place in 1997 to make Baek 1.5 million dollars in debt. This failure made him feel so hopeless about the future that he decided to kill himself in Hong Kong.<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup></p>
<p>When arrived in Hong Kong, Baek realized drowning himself in the river is not a good idea since he’s a decent swimmer. Also, jumping from the buildings is impossible because he could not even access the rooftops. So, in Hong Kong, Baek failed to commit suicide but ended up eating tons of great food before “dying.”</p>
<p>Eventually, the food he ate in Hong Kong inspired Baek to realize the fact that he still owns a restaurant to pay back the debt. Baek found his passion for food when he failed to end his life.</p>
<p>Back in Korea, Baek began to convince the creditors to wait until his restaurant becomes successful. And, as we all know, he only needed a few years to keep his promise. His company The Born began to launch successful brands such as Hanshin Pocha in 1998, Bornga in 2002, Paik’s BBQ in 2005, and Paik’s Coffee in 2006.</p>
<h3 id="baeks-wisdom">Baek’s wisdom</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>Do what you like. My work doesn’t feel like work. I don’t care how much time I spend thinking about food. I just feel so happy. - <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AdCPchhqTac">Baek Jong-won</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Baek has shared his insight through several essays and videos. These are some of his ideas that have resonated with me:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p><em>Be genuine</em> — “You don’t have to force yourself to be kind to the customers. Be kind when your heart tells you to.”</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Don’t overthink</em> — “Don’t drown yourself with the numbers and market analysis. When testing a new brand, I ask my employees to raise hands if they think the price and quality are satisfactory. I never think too much.”</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Customer experience is multifaceted</em> — “When someone likes your restaurant. The taste of your food can only be 30% of the reason. 70% of the reason is the restaurant’s ambiance.”</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Think big</em> — “I have so many brands that have never been shown to the public. Before launching a restaurant, we aim to have 2-300 restaurants all over the country … Don’t ask your friends before making a decision. Think about what the majority of people actually want.”</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Conviction matters</em> — “Don’t invite your family when you open a restaurant. They’ll try to contribute by saying something like ‘too salty’ or ‘too sweet.’ You must be aware that every individual tastes food differently. Just believe in yourself.”</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Have skin in the game</em> — “Successful restaurant owners I know have never received help from the business consultants. The consultants will tell you that they worked for these great brands, but they’ve never built anything on their own.”</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="baeks-legacy-does-not-end-here">Baek’s legacy does not end here</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>I never knew I would think like this today. I originally started my business to make money. When people started to give compliments, I began to care about what others think about me. I suddenly wanted to become a role model. - <a href="https://www.donga.com/news/Entertainment/article/all/20190302/94360231/1">Baek Jong-won</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Once thought of killing himself, Baek continues to launch new restaurant brands, host successful tv shows, and <a href="https://www.chosun.com/site/data/html_dir/2020/08/12/2020081203886.html#:~:text=%EB%B0%B1%EC%A2%85%EC%9B%90%EC%9D%80%20%EC%A7%80%EB%82%9C%202015%EB%85%84,%EC%A1%B4%EC%A4%91%EA%B8%B0%EA%B8%88%EC%97%90%20%EA%B8%B0%EB%B6%80%ED%96%88%EB%8B%A4.">donate</a> hundreds and thousands of dollars for people like low-income households and flood victims.<sup id="fnref:6"><a href="#fn:6" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">6</a></sup></p>
<p>Baek’s unflinching passion for food inspires me because he has created a new market that suits his passion. Will Baek be successful forever? Nobody knows. But, Baek sure will be one the happiest Koreans as long as he can make build out of his passion.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Although The Born is based in Korea, its restaurants have reached other countries like Japan, China, Vietnam, Singapore, Australia, and the United States.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>My Little Television featured several guests who had to stream original content like the creators on Twitch.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>Baek will also be hosting Baek’s Spirit in collaboration with Netflix.&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>The restaurant is famous for “the first restaurant to serve 대패 삼겹살 (thin-sliced pork belly).”&#160;<a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p>Baek had never been to Hong Kong but thought it would be the ideal place to die. Probably influenced by some movies of Hong Kong.&#160;<a href="#fnref:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:6">
<p>Also, Baek’s face can be found on products like a lunch box, multi-purpose sauce, and canned pork.&#160;<a href="#fnref:6" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Stories of McDonald&#39;s, Shake Shack, In-N-Out, Egg Slut, and Blue Bottle in South Korea</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/american-food-chains/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/blog/american-food-chains/</guid>
      <description>It all starts with a McDonald’s The first McDonald’s in Korea was opened in 1988. Throughout the opening day of the first McDonald’s, the restaurant’s 140 workers had to serve more than 3,000 customers.1 The Korean people&amp;rsquo;s passion for Big Mac happened more than 30 years ago, and now you can find more than 400 McDonald’s in this country.&#xA;It’s not just McDonald’s though. There are now hundreds of other fast-food chains all over the country, such as Burger King, Lotteria, and No Brand Burger.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="it-all-starts-with-a-mcdonalds">It all starts with a McDonald’s</h3>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663332851.jpg" alt="Image title"></p>
<p><a href="https://www.donga.com/news/Economy/article/all/20180325/89292785/1">The first McDonald’s in Korea</a> was opened in 1988. Throughout the opening day of the first McDonald’s, the restaurant’s 140 workers had to serve more than <a href="https://post.naver.com/viewer/postView.nhn?volumeNo=16800268&amp;memberNo=42569103">3,000 customers</a>.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> The Korean people&rsquo;s passion for Big Mac happened more than 30 years ago, and now you can find more than 400 McDonald’s in this country.</p>
<p>It’s not just McDonald’s though. There are now hundreds of other fast-food chains all over the country, such as Burger King, Lotteria, and No Brand Burger. For Koreans today, there should be nothing exciting left for ordering American-style burgers &amp; fries.</p>
<p>However, the brands like Shake Shack, Eggslut, and In-N-Out Burger have somehow managed to create the same level of hype that worked for McDonald’s in 1988.</p>
<p>Why? Let’s first check what happened when these restaurants opened their first spot in Korea.</p>
<h3 id="shake-shack">Shake Shack</h3>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663332877.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<p>On July 22nd, 2016, Shake Shack opened its doors in Gangnam district of Seoul. The city’s excitement was through the roof; there were even people waiting the night before(just like how people used to sleep in front of an Apple Store).<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup></p>
<p>The line did not become any shorter for months; 4,000~5,000 customers had to wait at least an hour to experience the shack. As a result, in the opening year, Shake Shack Gangnam <a href="http://koreabizwire.com/shake-shack-burger-in-s-korea-tops-in-global-sales/76398">reported</a> daily selling of 3,000~3,500 burgers, becoming the largest revenue-generator among 120 Shake Shack branches around the world.</p>
<h3 id="eggslut">Eggslut</h3>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663332903.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<p>Four years later, another sandwich chain from America named Eggslut arrived at COEX mall located in Gangnam district of Seoul.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> On the first day, when the doors were not even open, there were already about three hundred people waiting outside.</p>
<p>In 2021, the hype continued at Eggslut’s second branch in the brand new department store called the Hyundai Seoul. Hundreds of people flocked to the place for the famous egg sandwich. And of course, everyone had to wait at least 1-2 hours.</p>
<p>During the first week, Eggslut’s second location sold more than 2,000 Fairfax Sandwiches every day. Of course, the egg sandwich place has instantly become <a href="https://www.asiae.co.kr/article/2021022721512831813">the most successful restaurant</a> in the mall.</p>
<h3 id="in-n-out">In-N-Out</h3>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663332923.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<p>In-N-Out Burger does not even have a branch in Korea, but the chain occasionally opens up a pop-up store in Seoul.<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup> For example, in 2019, the restaurant opened a 3-hour pop-up store in Gangnam district.</p>
<p>This time, the line began to form around 5:30 AM and there were already more than three hundred people waiting around 11 AM. In-N-Out had prepared around 250 burgers for the day, so the pop-up could not even last 3 hours.</p>
<h3 id="lets-pause-for-a-moment-to-underline-the-patterns">Let’s pause for a moment to underline the patterns.</h3>
<p>We’ve observed that McDonald’s, Shake Shack, and Eggslut all opened their first locations in Gangnam district, made hundreds of people wait in line, and created the initial hype to fuel the rapid growth.<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup></p>
<p>Do these patterns only apply to those fast-food chains that serve burgers and fries?</p>
<h3 id="enters-blue-bottle">Enters Blue Bottle</h3>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663332943.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<p>Cafes are literally everywhere in this country. According to the data from 2020, there are 83,692 coffee shops in Korea, and 18,535 of them are located in Seoul.<sup id="fnref:6"><a href="#fn:6" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">6</a></sup> Because of this extremely competitive environment, about 50% of new cafes close their business within <a href="https://www.sedaily.com/NewsVIew/1Z1NVAXATT#:~:text=%EC%84%9C%EC%9A%B8%EC%97%90%EC%84%9C%20%EB%AC%B8%EC%9D%84%20%EC%97%B0,%EC%A4%91%20%EC%B5%9C%EA%B3%A0%EC%B9%98%EB%A5%BC%20%EA%B8%B0%EB%A1%9D%ED%96%88%EB%8B%A4">three years</a>.</p>
<p>No doubt, there are a lot of great coffee shops that brew excellent coffee for a reasonable price.<sup id="fnref:7"><a href="#fn:7" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">7</a></sup> However, none of the Korean-born cafes can expect to create a line as long as that of the first Blue Bottle Coffee.</p>
<p>In May 2019, a long line began to form around 5 AM outside the first Blue Bottle Coffee in Seoul. Some people had brought blankets and pillows so they could be one of the first to enter the store. When the shop opened its doors at 8 AM, there were more than 200 people in line and the number grew to over 400 within an hour.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.hankyung.com/economy/article/201905098280i">Reportedly</a>, the customers spent more than ₩60,000,000(~$53,000) on the opening day alone, and this was the new sales record for the global brand that had 70 other branches in the U.S. and Japan.</p>
<p>Now, Blue Bottle has 7 different branches in Seoul, including the newest one near the second branch of Eggslut.</p>
<h3 id="tartine-bakery">Tartine Bakery</h3>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663332959.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<p><strong>Jan 2018. The opening day of Tartine Bakery Seoul</strong></p>
<p>As of today, Tartine has 7 locations in the U.S.: four in Bay Area and three in LA. The bakery does not even have a branch in U.S. cities like Portland, Seattle, and New York.</p>
<p>Anyways, instead of expanding nationally, Tartine chose Korea to be the next ground for its business. In other words, <a href="http://www.mediapen.com/news/view/325161">young Korean chaebols</a> were able to convince the bakery to open up spots in their country.</p>
<p>When the bakery opened its doors in Hannam-dong, every single piece of bread in the store was sold out <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.kr/news/articleView.html?idxno=64274">within hours</a>.<sup id="fnref:8"><a href="#fn:8" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">8</a></sup> And now, Tartine has 6 different locations in Seoul.</p>
<h3 id="randys-donuts">Randy’s Donuts</h3>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663332979.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<p>In August 2019, the first Randy’s Donuts Korea was open in Jeju. Now the donut chain has three different locations in Seoul, Daegu, and Jeju. And of course, you always have to wait in line for at least 20-30 minutes to taste some of the American-style donuts.</p>
<h3 id="tiger-sugar">Tiger Sugar</h3>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/kang-1663332994.webp" alt="Image title"></p>
<p>Tiger Sugar, a Taiwanese bubble tea chain famous for its brown sugar boba, entered Korea in 2019. And Tiger Sugar did not have to wait for success; for the entire summer in 2019, people waited at least 30 minutes to take a picture with the drink’s “tiger stripes.”</p>
<p>The story of Tiger Sugar demonstrates that non-American food chains can also create a similar type of hype as Shake Shack or Blue Bottle. In 2021, Tiger Sugar runs more than 40 different locations all over Korea.</p>
<p><em>Update: It&rsquo;s been a year since I wrote this. Most of the Tiger Sugar stores have been closed in Korea. Maybe it is extremely difficult for a non-US brand to sustain the hype.</em></p>
<h3 id="finally-why">Finally.. Why?</h3>
<p>Maybe showing off on Instagram gets all the credit for the success of these American(sometimes Taiwanese) “fine casual” chains in Korea. However, there must be many more factors that contribute to the psychology of people who are willing to sacrifice hours for a simple bite.</p>
<p>So, here’s my take:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>In 2018, more than 2 million people from Korea visited the U.S., and this number is almost twice as big as the data from 2010.<sup id="fnref:9"><a href="#fn:9" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">9</a></sup> What did these tourists do when they visited cities like LA and New York? I bet a lot of them went to Insta-famous spots like Eggslut and Shake Shack. And when these “former tourists” realized that these American chains were now available in Korea, they immediately brought up the &ldquo;touristified&rdquo; memories of these restaurants. And to relive the excitement he/she had as a tourist, waiting for hours could feel like a small investment.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Korean society is pretty boring. The economy is controlled by a handful of chaebols like Samsung, Hyundai, and SK. The dream jobs for most youngsters are <a href="https://www.hani.co.kr/arti/economy/economy_general/817939.html">“stable” ones</a> such as government workers, public school teachers, and whatever that is related to Samsung. In this homogeneous society, lots of people aspire to differentiate themselves from others. And becoming the first one to experience the hype could be one of the most accessible ways to do that.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>In Korea, the offline retail market is controlled by chaebol companies like Shinsegae, Lotte, and Hyundai. These conglomerates own fancy department stores, shopping malls, and hotels. However, we all know that a big portion of the offline business is going online. Then how do these luxurious shopping areas and hotels win the battle against each other? Seems like the answer is hosting Eggslut and Blue Bottle just like what Hyundai Seoul did this year. Not only Hyundai Seoul, but also places like Ryse Hotel, Central City, and Times Square Mall have embraced “fine casual” restaurants like Shake Shack and Tartine.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Korean media is notorious for glamorizing American culture: whenever there’s a new plan to support startups, articles use the expressions like <a href="http://www.sandannews.co.kr/news/articleView.html?idxno=790">“Korean Silicon Valley”</a> or <a href="http://www.slist.kr/news/articleView.html?idxno=231411">“Korean Steve Jobs.”</a> Renowned investors like John Lee and Kang Bang-cheon are called “Warren Buffett of Korea.” Harvard-polished books like <em>Justice</em> and <em>Methods of Logic</em> have stayed the best sellers for years. Parasite winning the Oscars is considered as an achievement that deserves national celebration.<sup id="fnref:10"><a href="#fn:10" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">10</a></sup> So yeah, when a restaurant group becomes successful in the U.S., Korean media and PR companies start to pump out phrases like <a href="https://www.hani.co.kr/arti/economy/consumer/892519.html">“Apple of coffee industry,”</a> <a href="https://biz.newdaily.co.kr/site/data/html/2016/07/12/2016071210019.html">“New York specialty,”</a> and <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.kr/news/articleView.html?idxno=64274">“the bread you must try before you die.”</a> And these messages eventually spread a major FOMO alert.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Or these restaurants, cafes, and bakeries are actually worth waiting for.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>McDonald’s chose Apgujeong-dong of Gangnam district as the first location.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Waiting outside for hours during summer in Seoul is no joke. The temperatures range from 85°F to 95°F.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>COEX is the largest underground shopping mall in Seoul. The place has <a href="https://korean.visitseoul.net/attractions/%EB%B3%84%EB%A7%88%EB%8B%B9-%EB%8F%84%EC%84%9C%EA%B4%80_/26558">an awful library</a> that uses books as decorations. Both Shake Shack and Eggslut were brought to Korea by SPC Group, which is one of the most prominent food conglomerates/chaebols in Korea.&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>Most likely, In-N-Out opens these pop-up stores to protect its trademark rights in Korea.&#160;<a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p>Even amid the pandemic, McDonald’s in Korea <a href="https://jhealthmedia.joins.com/article/article_view.asp?pno=21944#:~:text=%ED%98%84%EC%9E%AC%20%ED%95%9C%EA%B5%AD%EB%A7%A5%EB%8F%84%EB%82%A0%EB%93%9C%EB%8A%94%20%EC%A0%84%EA%B5%AD,%EB%A7%A4%EC%9E%A5%EC%9D%84%20%EC%9A%B4%EC%98%81%ED%95%98%EA%B3%A0%20%EC%9E%88%EB%8B%A4">reported</a> a 9% growth in revenue this year.&#160;<a href="#fnref:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:6">
<p>Also, <a href="https://health.chosun.com/site/data/html_dir/2020/07/08/2020070802598.html#:~:text=%ED%95%98%EB%A3%A8%20%ED%8F%89%EA%B7%A0%20%EC%BB%A4%ED%94%BC%20%EC%84%AD%EC%B7%A8%EB%9F%89%EC%9D%80,(1.7%EC%9E%94)%EB%B3%B4%EB%8B%A4%20%EB%A7%8E%EC%95%98%EB%8B%A4">on average</a>, a Korean adult drinks 1.8 cups of coffee every day.&#160;<a href="#fnref:6" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:7">
<p>In Seongsu-dong, I recommend visiting Lowkey Coffee and Momento Brewers.&#160;<a href="#fnref:7" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:8">
<p>Hannam-dong is known as one of the wealthiest neighborhoods in Seoul.&#160;<a href="#fnref:8" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:9">
<p>Apparently, the number fell dramatically after the pandemic.&#160;<a href="#fnref:9" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:10">
<p>I’m not saying Parasite did not deserve the awards. I’m just saying great movies like Parasite should be celebrated regardless of the Academy’s acceptance.&#160;<a href="#fnref:10" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Postcard Design</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/postcard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/postcard/</guid>
      <description> Here is my latest postcard design. Click on the image to see both sides of the postcard. Download Postcard with Message&#xA;Download 300 DPI PNG&#xA;Download 600 DPI PNG&#xA;Download 1200 DPI PNG </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="postcard-container">
  <div class="postcard" id="postcard">
    <img id="front" src="/images/postcard_front.jpg" alt="Postcard Front" class="front">
    <div class="back-container" id="back-container">
      <img id="back" src="/images/postcard_back.jpg" alt="Postcard Back" class="back">
      <textarea id="message" placeholder="Write your message here..."></textarea>
    </div>
  </div>
  <p class="intro">
    Here is my latest postcard design. Click on the image to see both sides of the postcard.
  </p>
  <div class="download-links">
    <a href="#" id="download-link">Download Postcard with Message</a><br>
    <a href="/files/postcard_300dpi.png" download>Download 300 DPI PNG</a><br>
    <a href="/files/postcard_600dpi.png" download>Download 600 DPI PNG</a><br>
    <a href="/files/postcard_1200dpi.png" download>Download 1200 DPI PNG</a>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thank you!</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/thank-you/</guid>
      <description>Your message has been sent.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<style>
  p.byline {display: none;}
  footer {display: none;}
  textarea {width: fit-content;}
  button,
  input,
  select,
  content,
  textarea {
  font-size: 100%;
}
</style>
<p>Your message has been sent.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>말머리씨</title>
      <link>https://kangminsuk.com/mal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kangminsuk.com/mal/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the video tag. &amp;ldquo;사람은 서울로, 말을 제주로.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;그래서 말머리씨는 제주에 삽니다.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Humans to Seoul, Horses to Jeju.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;That&amp;rsquo;s why Mal-muh-lee lives in Jeju.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<style>
  body {
    text-align: center;
  }
</style>
<div class="video-container">
  <video autoplay loop muted>
    <source src="/videos/animation.mp4" type="video/mp4">
    Your browser does not support the video tag.
  </video>
</div>
<p>&ldquo;사람은 서울로, 말을 제주로.&rdquo;</p>
<p>그래서 말머리씨는 제주에 삽니다.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Humans to Seoul, Horses to Jeju.&rdquo;</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s why Mal-muh-lee lives in Jeju.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
